<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Life on Simone Mattioli</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/tags/life.html</link><description>Recent content in Life on Simone Mattioli</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:31:32 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://simo-hue.github.io/tags/life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Ignorance in the modern day is a choice</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/02_thought/ignorance-today.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:31:32 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/02_thought/ignorance-today.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="to-do">to do&lt;/h2></description></item><item><title>Life Appreciation</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/02_thought/gratitude.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:31:32 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/02_thought/gratitude.html</guid><description>&lt;p>We often live in a rush, projected towards new goals and expectations. In this vortex, we can take for granted what we have: our health, our family, the people who love us, or even the simple warmth of the sun on our skin. Yet, when we learn to stop and really “see” these things, we discover a source of serenity and strength that can change our way of living.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-beauty-of-everyday-life">&lt;strong>The Beauty of Everyday Life&lt;/strong>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Being grateful does not only mean recognizing great achievements or resounding successes, but also stopping to observe what surrounds us. It may seem trivial, but appreciating a morning coffee, a sincere smile, or the hug of a dear friend has immense value. These moments remind us that happiness does not lie in great events, but in the sum of many small moments lived with awareness.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Personal Growth</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/05_passions/persona-growth.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:31:32 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/05_passions/persona-growth.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img alt="as" src="https://simo-hue.github.io/05_passions/persona-growth/personalgrowth.jpg">
Embark on a journey of &lt;strong>personal growth&lt;/strong> and self-discovery! This blog is all about transforming life, one article, one book, and one action at a time. Starting with a simple curiosity, I dove into the world of personal development, reading about habits, resilience, mindfulness, and purpose. Each insight led to real changes in how I see myself, set goals, and make decisions. Here, I’ll share lessons from books and articles that have had the biggest impact on my life, along with actionable tips and reflections on the changes I’ve experienced. Join me in exploring the power of intentional self-improvement and see how small shifts can lead to profound personal transformation&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>