<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Who's Simone Mattioli? on Simone Mattioli</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/</link><description>Recent content in Who's Simone Mattioli? on Simone Mattioli</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://simo-hue.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>NO MAFIA, Sicily Tour with LIA Rovereto</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/04_experiences/sicily.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/04_experiences/sicily.html</guid><description>&lt;p>tour sicilia, da implementare&lt;/p>
&lt;p>TO DO:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>passarsi tutte le foto orizzontali&lt;/li>
&lt;li>fare table di tutte le cose che abbiamo fatto&lt;/li>
&lt;li>premesse &amp;amp; aspettative&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Contesto storico&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Stazione di capaci&lt;/li>
&lt;li>buncherino&lt;/li>
&lt;li>palermo&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Segno della resistenza sulla scrivania di Borsellino -&amp;gt; ( l&amp;rsquo;ho interpretato come ) la resistenza e resilienza che ogni essere umano ( Di successo ) deve avere&lt;/li>
&lt;li>determinazione che ci vuole per raggiungere grandi cose&lt;/li>
&lt;li>testimonianza del fotografo ( magari nei thought mettere che siamo una generazione che si smagnetizzerà -&amp;gt; problema del digitale )&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Come vogliono rappresentare la loro terra ( senso di appartenenza / eliminazione degli stereotipi)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>La differenza tra una guida &amp;ldquo;normale&amp;rdquo; del 99% ed il top 1% ( come in ogni settore si può eccellere e non)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Spread Love wherever you go</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/02_thought/love.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/02_thought/love.html</guid><description>&lt;p>We are always &amp;hellip; da completare&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="why">&lt;strong>Why&lt;/strong>&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="dont-do-it-to-much">&lt;strong>Don&amp;rsquo;t Do It To much&lt;/strong>&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Not everyone is able to do it, but you must be one of them&amp;hellip;Simo&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>The importance of being able to stay alone</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/02_thought/alone.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/02_thought/alone.html</guid><description>&lt;p>We are always &amp;hellip; da completare&lt;/p>
&lt;p>importanza di conoscerese stessi
capire che non + normale sempere essere circondati da persona, soprattutto non sentire la pressione sociale da parte dei propri pari mentre si è in un gruppo del quale non si vorrebbe fare parte&lt;/p>
&lt;p>sj diventa indipenti da altre persone, quindi anche più forti&lt;/p>
&lt;p>capire il valore della solitudine, molti pensieri vengono in mente e anche nmolte idee se questi momenti però vengono vissuti e sfruttati in un certo modo altrimenti se ci si circonda solamente di stimoli negativi quali i social non si va da nessuna parte e la solitudine richia di diventare depressione invece che una palestra per crescere come persona&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Daniele Cassioli</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/02_thought/cassioli.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/02_thought/cassioli.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Essere grato per essere nel collegio di merito don mazza di verona e per le opportunità che mi venogo fornite da questo collegio&lt;/p>
&lt;p>parlare della fonazione ( &lt;a href="https://www.danielecassioli.it">https://www.danielecassioli.it&lt;/a> )&lt;/p>
&lt;p>consapevolezza piu profonda dei normodotati&lt;/p>
&lt;p>doti che ha sviluppato&lt;/p>
&lt;p>importanza di saper ironizzare i propri difetti, sfortune per vivere una vita più serena ed impace con se stessi&lt;/p>
&lt;p>dei suoi libri ( uno che ho letto )&lt;/p>
&lt;p>del quanto fare sport sia importante per il benessere e la felicità di una persona&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Don't Brag</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/02_thought/humility.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/02_thought/humility.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="the-importance-of-humility-but-without-losing-self-confidence">The importance of humility, but without losing self-confidence&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Humility is one of the most appreciated and sought-after qualities, both in personal and professional life. Being humble helps us grow, learn from others and recognize that we do not always have all the answers. It allows us to approach people with respect, creating authentic relationships based on mutual esteem. But it is important to remember that, like all virtues, humility must also be cultivated with balance.
&lt;img src="https://simo-hue.github.io/02_thought/humility/napkin-selection-4.png">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>History importance</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/02_thought/history.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/02_thought/history.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="my-journey-from-hater-to-curious">My Journey from Hater to Curious&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>I admit that history was my nemesis during my school years. When the professor entered the classroom and started talking about dates, battles and rulers, I felt lost. It all seemed so boring and distant from my reality. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t perceive the value of that knowledge: why on earth would I be interested in what had happened centuries ago?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Over the years, however, something changed. I began to realize my gaps, feeling ashamed of how little I knew about our past (not with others but with myself). I understood that ignoring history was not only an academic shortcoming, but a real limitation in understanding the world around me.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>repetition is the mother of all skills</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/02_thought/humility.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/02_thought/humility.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="the-importance-of-repetition">The importance of repetition&lt;/h1></description></item><item><title>Atomic Habits | James Clear</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/06_books/atomic-habits.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:31:32 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/06_books/atomic-habits.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="prova">PROVA&lt;/h1></description></item><item><title>Cars</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/05_passions/car.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:31:32 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/05_passions/car.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Fueled by passion and the unforgettable roar of petrol engines, this blog is a tribute to the timeless allure of cars. From a young age, I was mesmerized by the hum of engines, the thrill of watching cars fly by on the road, and the unmistakable connection I felt with each machine. Here, I dive into everything that makes cars more than just vehicles—from the technical finesse of engineering to the pure adrenaline sparked by the sound of a finely-tuned engine. Join me as I explore the art, performance, and culture of cars, where every drive feels like a shared heartbeat between driver and machine.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Guadagna con la mente |</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/06_books/mente-guadagna.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:31:32 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/06_books/mente-guadagna.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="prova">PROVA&lt;/h1></description></item><item><title>guida ai bias cognitivi</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/06_books/bias-cognitivi.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:31:32 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/06_books/bias-cognitivi.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="prova">PROVA&lt;/h1></description></item><item><title>Ignorance in the modern day is a choice</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/02_thought/ignorance-today.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:31:32 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/02_thought/ignorance-today.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="to-do">to do&lt;/h2></description></item><item><title>il grifone | Nicola Gratteri</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/06_books/gratteri.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:31:32 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/06_books/gratteri.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="prova">PROVA&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>paragone con borsellino, da delle interviste ho sentito che dedica tutta la sua vita al lavoro e ho trovato questa analogia&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>il vento contro | Daniele Cassioli</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/06_books/cassioli-ventro-contro.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:31:32 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/06_books/cassioli-ventro-contro.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="prova">PROVA&lt;/h1></description></item><item><title>insegna al cuore a vedere | Daniele Cassioli</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/06_books/cassioli-cuore-a-vedere.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:31:32 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/06_books/cassioli-cuore-a-vedere.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="prova">PROVA&lt;/h1></description></item><item><title>Life Appreciation</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/02_thought/gratitude.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:31:32 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/02_thought/gratitude.html</guid><description>&lt;p>We often live in a rush, projected towards new goals and expectations. In this vortex, we can take for granted what we have: our health, our family, the people who love us, or even the simple warmth of the sun on our skin. Yet, when we learn to stop and really “see” these things, we discover a source of serenity and strength that can change our way of living.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-beauty-of-everyday-life">&lt;strong>The Beauty of Everyday Life&lt;/strong>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Being grateful does not only mean recognizing great achievements or resounding successes, but also stopping to observe what surrounds us. It may seem trivial, but appreciating a morning coffee, a sincere smile, or the hug of a dear friend has immense value. These moments remind us that happiness does not lie in great events, but in the sum of many small moments lived with awareness.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Motorbikes</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/05_passions/motorbike.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:31:32 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/05_passions/motorbike.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img alt="My Fantic 50 Motard" src="https://simo-hue.github.io/05_passions/motorbike/fantic.jpg">
Born from a lifelong craving for the thrill of two wheels, this blog captures the essence of my journey into the world of motorbikes. Ever since I was young, I dreamt of owning my own bike, and when I finally got my Fantic 50 2-stroke, it was everything I’d imagined—and more. From personalizing it to make it uniquely mine, to mastering the art of riding on one wheel, every ride brought a rush of freedom and exhilaration. Here, I’ll share stories, tips, and insights into the motorbike lifestyle, celebrating the pure adrenaline, skill, and connection that only bikers understand. Whether you’re a seasoned rider or just curious, join me on the ride!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mountain bike</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/05_passions/bike.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:31:32 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/05_passions/bike.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img alt="Me exploring the beauty of Rabbi Valley" src="https://simo-hue.github.io/05_passions/bike/mountainbike.jpg">
This blog is all about the adrenaline, freedom, and connection with nature that mountain biking has brought into my life. Ever since my first ride, I was hooked—there’s nothing like the thrill of hitting rugged trails, mastering new terrain, and feeling the rush of carving through mountainsides.
From discovering the best gear and customizing my setup to push my limits, to the pure satisfaction of conquering new trails, mountain biking has become more than a sport—it’s a passion. Here, I’ll share tips, personal stories, trail reviews, and everything that makes mountain biking an adventure worth chasing. Whether you’re a seasoned rider or a curious beginner, join me in exploring the world on two wheels!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mountain Hiking</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/05_passions/hiking.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:31:32 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/05_passions/hiking.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="prova">PROVA&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://simo-hue.github.io/05_passions/hiking/sfondo.JPG">
&lt;img src="https://simo-hue.github.io/05_passions/hiking/alba.JPG">
&lt;img src="https://simo-hue.github.io/05_passions/hiking/rabb.JPG">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pensa ed arrichisci te stesso</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/06_books/grow-rich.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:31:32 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/06_books/grow-rich.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="prova">PROVA&lt;/h1></description></item><item><title>Pensieri lenti pensieri veloci</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/06_books/pensieri-lenti-pensieri-veloci.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:31:32 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/06_books/pensieri-lenti-pensieri-veloci.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="prova">PROVA&lt;/h1></description></item><item><title>Personal Growth</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/05_passions/persona-growth.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:31:32 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/05_passions/persona-growth.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img alt="as" src="https://simo-hue.github.io/05_passions/persona-growth/personalgrowth.jpg">
Embark on a journey of &lt;strong>personal growth&lt;/strong> and self-discovery! This blog is all about transforming life, one article, one book, and one action at a time. Starting with a simple curiosity, I dove into the world of personal development, reading about habits, resilience, mindfulness, and purpose. Each insight led to real changes in how I see myself, set goals, and make decisions. Here, I’ll share lessons from books and articles that have had the biggest impact on my life, along with actionable tips and reflections on the changes I’ve experienced. Join me in exploring the power of intentional self-improvement and see how small shifts can lead to profound personal transformation&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Rich and Poor Dad</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/06_books/richpoor-dad.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:31:32 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/06_books/richpoor-dad.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="prova">PROVA&lt;/h1></description></item><item><title>Ski</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/05_passions/ski.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:31:32 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/05_passions/ski.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="prova">PROVA&lt;/h1></description></item><item><title>The 20th century Trap</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/02_thought/trap.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:31:32 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/02_thought/trap.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="detached-from-stimuli">Detached from stimuli&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>We live in an age of constant stimulation, a constant flow of notifications, updates and digital content that keep us constantly &amp;ldquo;connected&amp;rdquo; but, at the same time, drastically reduce our ability to concentrate. Every day, we are bombarded with visual and auditory stimuli through social media, messaging apps, entertainment platforms, which now guide our lives both online and offline.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-loss-of-attention-span">The Loss of Attention Span&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This situation scares me. I have noticed, especially during the pandemic, how much social media has taken on the role of &amp;ldquo;directors&amp;rdquo; of our lives. People talk about news, trends, and aspects of other people&amp;rsquo;s lives that they have learned on social media, as if these have replaced real experiences. Our attention span has reduced to almost absurd levels: we are incapable of standing in line or waiting without taking out our phones in search of new stimuli. This constant search for instant gratification through digital devices deprives us of the ability to fully live in the moment.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Birdwatching Experience with SWAROVSKI OPTIK at Le Ali del Frassino Residence (Lake Frassino)</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/04_experiences/frassino.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/04_experiences/frassino.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img alt="Logo Swarovski Optik" src="https://simo-hue.github.io/04_experiences/frassino/swarovski.jpeg">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recently, thanks to my project &lt;em>Mountain Fauna Lover&lt;/em>, I had the chance to participate in an exclusive event organized by SWAROVSKI OPTIK Italy at the stunning Frassino Oasis in Peschiera del Garda.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Mountain Fauna Lover&lt;/em> began almost as a joke, born from my love for mountains and wildlife. I never imagined it would open doors to such exciting collaborations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img alt="Bird Migration" src="https://simo-hue.github.io/04_experiences/frassino/migrazione.jpg">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Through this project, I’ve been able to experience nature up close, often alongside experts and using top-tier equipment, making each adventure more unforgettable than the last.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Don Mazza College</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/04_experiences/mazza.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/04_experiences/mazza.html</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Spiegare come l&amp;rsquo;ho trovato&lt;/li>
&lt;li>come mi sono trovato&lt;/li>
&lt;li>linkare il mio video &amp;ldquo;recensione&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Esperienze fatte:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>conoscenza di persone ( poche, 1 -&amp;gt; Vale )&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Condivisione&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Ore formative&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Viaggio di Budapest&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Confronto con gli altri coetanei&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>EPICURE Hackathon GPU - October 2024</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/03_projects/epicure-hackathon-2024.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/03_projects/epicure-hackathon-2024.html</guid><description>&lt;p>The &lt;strong>EPICURE Hackathon&lt;/strong>, held from October 28-31, 2024, brought together developers, researchers, and enthusiasts from across Europe to dive deep into the world of &lt;strong>GPU programming and high-performance computing (HPC)&lt;/strong>. This event was hosted in collaboration with &lt;strong>CINECA&lt;/strong>, one of the leading HPC centers in Europe, renowned for its contributions to scientific computing and advanced research.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The hackathon was meticulously structured, featuring both hands-on labs and theoretical sessions, designed to empower participants with the latest skills in &lt;strong>CUDA programming&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>OpenACC&lt;/strong>, and &lt;strong>GPU optimization techniques&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Volounteering Activity in Brazil</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/04_experiences/brazil.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/04_experiences/brazil.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;img alt="Don Mazza Logo" src="https://simo-hue.github.io/04_experiences/brazil/don-mazza-pia.jpg">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My volunteer experience in Brazil was an unforgettable journey that led me to discover not only a country rich in culture, but also the daily challenges faced by people in vulnerable situations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We left in seven, a heterogeneous group composed of six strangers from different Italian cities: Verona, Padua and Rome. The experience was organized by &lt;strong>Collegio Di Merito Don Mazza&lt;/strong>, an institution that promotes social commitment and volunteering as well as providing accommodation for university students.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>21th birth Day in Brazil</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/04_experiences/21th-birthday.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/04_experiences/21th-birthday.html</guid><description>&lt;p>My 21st birthday was unique, an experience I will never forget. I spent it in Brazil, during my volunteering period, far from home and all my loved ones. On that occasion, I was not surrounded by the familiar faces of friends and relatives, but by six strangers, who shared with me the experience of volunteering in a country so different from mine.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img alt="Relaxing morning in Olinda beach" src="https://simo-hue.github.io/04_experiences/21th-birthday/spiaggia.png">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I did not expect anything special. Usually, birthdays have never had a particular meaning for me, but that day turned out to be different, special, unique. Celebrating a birthday far from home and loved ones was a first step out of my comfort zone. It allowed me to live the moment with lightness and curiosity, immersed in a new experience.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mountain Fauna Lover</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/03_projects/mountain-fauna-lover.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/03_projects/mountain-fauna-lover.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Welcome to MountainFaunaLover! Here, I share my passion for nature, wildlife, and the captivating landscapes of mountain regions. On Instagram, you’ll find a curated collection of my favorite moments in the wilderness, from up-close shots of unique wildlife to breathtaking mountain vistas. Each post is a window into my adventures, capturing the serenity, beauty, and diversity of the natural world that inspires me daily.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On YouTube, I dive even deeper. My channel is a space for storytelling, featuring video journeys, wildlife encounters, and conservation insights, bringing viewers along on my explorations. Whether you’re a fellow nature enthusiast or just stopping by for some visual serenity, my content on MountainFaunaLover is dedicated to sharing the awe and importance of our wild places. Join me in celebrating the mountains, fauna, and the fascinating stories they hold!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Simo's Online &amp; Digital Diary</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/03_projects/home.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/03_projects/home.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Welcome to simo&amp;rsquo;s Diary, a place where I love to share&amp;hellip;.da completare&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="scopri-il-mio-canale-youtube-simos-diary">Scopri il Mio Canale YouTube: Simo&amp;rsquo;s Diary&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Oggi voglio parlarvi del mio canale YouTube, &lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/@SimosDiary2003">Simo&amp;rsquo;s Diary&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>, dove condivido momenti della mia vita, progetti personali e passioni. Questo spazio nasce dal desiderio di documentare le mie esperienze in modo autentico e trasparente, mostrandovi viaggi, avventure e molto altro ancora.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="perché-ho-creato-simos-diary">Perché Ho Creato Simo&amp;rsquo;s Diary?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Viviamo in un&amp;rsquo;epoca in cui la tecnologia ci permette di catturare momenti in alta qualità semplicemente con uno smartphone. Non voglio sprecare questa opportunità! Anzi, penso sia fantastico poter registrare e condividere pezzi della mia vita che, altrimenti, resterebbero solo nella memoria. Con Simo&amp;rsquo;s Diary, non solo posso raccogliere questi ricordi per il futuro, ma anche condividerli con chiunque voglia seguirli e magari trovare ispirazione.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Search</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/search.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/search.html</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>