<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Simone Mattioli</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/</link><description>Recent content on Simone Mattioli</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Wheelchair Basketball</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/04_experiences/basket-in-carrozzina/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/04_experiences/basket-in-carrozzina/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="an-experience-that-changes-your-perspective-wheelchair-basketball">An Experience That Changes Your Perspective: Wheelchair Basketball&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Thanks to the extraordinary collaboration between &lt;strong>Collegio Don Mazza&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Residenza Ferrari delle Spade di Verona&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Olympic Basket Verona&lt;/strong>, I had the opportunity to live one of the most significant experiences of my life: trying &lt;strong>wheelchair basketball&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/01_home/simone-mattioli/04_experiences/basket-in-carrozzina/me.jpeg" alt="This is Me having fun trying this new unbelivable sport">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="a-unique-experience">A unique experience&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This discipline goes far beyond a simple game. It is a real lesson in strength, determination and inclusion. Sitting in a wheelchair, picking up the ball and trying to move, shoot and collaborate with the rest of the team was enlightening.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Relationship Importance</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/02_thought/relationship/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/02_thought/relationship/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="friendship-and-love">Friendship and Love&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Human relationships are the fundamental pillar of our existence, it is no coincidence that it is said that man is a social animal&amp;hellip; Friendships, family ties and romantic relationships contribute to defining not only the quality of our life, but also who we are and what we can become. We cannot ignore the enormous impact that these connections have on us, for better or for worse, and on our lives.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>NO MAFIA Sicily Tour</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/04_experiences/sicily/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/04_experiences/sicily/</guid><description>&lt;p>tour sicilia, da implementare&lt;/p>
&lt;p>TO DO:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>passarsi tutte le foto orizzontali&lt;/li>
&lt;li>fare table di tutte le cose che abbiamo fatto&lt;/li>
&lt;li>premesse &amp;amp; aspettative&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Contesto storico&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Stazione di capaci&lt;/li>
&lt;li>buncherino&lt;/li>
&lt;li>palermo&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Segno della resistenza sulla scrivania di Borsellino -&amp;gt; ( l&amp;rsquo;ho interpretato come ) la resistenza e resilienza che ogni essere umano ( Di successo ) deve avere&lt;/li>
&lt;li>determinazione che ci vuole per raggiungere grandi cose&lt;/li>
&lt;li>testimonianza del fotografo ( magari nei thought mettere che siamo una generazione che si smagnetizzerà -&amp;gt; problema del digitale )&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Come vogliono rappresentare la loro terra ( senso di appartenenza / eliminazione degli stereotipi)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>La differenza tra una guida &amp;ldquo;normale&amp;rdquo; del 99% ed il top 1% ( come in ogni settore si può eccellere e non)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>

 &lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
 &lt;iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" loading="eager" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/RdgWMgmqqHk?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" title="YouTube video">&lt;/iframe>
 &lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Spread Love wherever you go</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/02_thought/love/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/02_thought/love/</guid><description>&lt;p>Kindness is one of those little gestures that make days brighter, both for the giver and the receiver. I have always found comfort in being kind to others, even in the simplest actions. A smile, a greeting, a “how are you?” may seem insignificant, but they often have a profound impact. They are small acts that cost nothing, but that bring enormous wealth.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I like to think that every little kindness is a seed of happiness that spreads around us. From holding a door open for those who follow, to giving a coin to someone in need, to giving a smile to someone in need. These gestures not only make others feel better, but they also fill my heart with joy. And more often than not, I realize that, without even wanting to, I have given a smile to someone else.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The importance of being able to stay alone</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/02_thought/alone/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/02_thought/alone/</guid><description>&lt;p>Knowing how to be alone is an often underestimated skill, but it is incredibly important for our personal growth. In a world that seems to constantly push us to seek the company of others, taking time for ourselves can be a revolutionary act. Not only does it allow us to know ourselves better, but it can turn into a real training ground for growing as a person.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="know-yourself">Know Yourself&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Solitude is a precious space to get in touch with ourselves. When we are alone, without distractions, we can listen to our thoughts and discover who we really are. What makes us happy? What do we want from life? What are our values? These are questions that we rarely find the time to address, but which can guide us towards a more authentic life.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Daniele Cassioli</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/02_thought/cassioli/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/02_thought/cassioli/</guid><description>&lt;p>I had the privilege of meeting Daniele Cassioli, and I can say that it was a deeply enriching experience. For those who don&amp;rsquo;t know him, Daniele is a blind Paralympic athlete, world champion in water skiing, author and motivational speaker. His story is an extraordinary example of how to transform difficulties into opportunities, and his way of life is a lesson that leads to reflection.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="gratitude-for-opportunities">Gratitude for Opportunities&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Being a student at the Collegio di Merito Don Mazza in Verona is an opportunity that has allowed me to participate in significant events like this. Meetings like this are precious opportunities to grow and look at the world with different eyes. I can only be grateful for everything that this college offers me, not only in terms of training, but also in terms of inspiration and awareness.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Don't Brag</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/02_thought/humility/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/02_thought/humility/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="the-importance-of-humility-but-without-losing-self-confidence">The importance of humility, but without losing self-confidence&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Humility is one of the most appreciated and sought-after qualities, both in personal and professional life. Being humble helps us grow, learn from others and recognize that we do not always have all the answers. It allows us to approach people with respect, creating authentic relationships based on mutual esteem. But it is important to remember that, like all virtues, humility must also be cultivated with balance.
&lt;img src="https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/01_home/simone-mattioli/02_thought/humility/napkin-selection-4.png" alt="">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>History importance</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/02_thought/history/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/02_thought/history/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="my-journey-from-hater-to-curious">My Journey from Hater to Curious&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>I admit that history was my nemesis during my school years. When the professor entered the classroom and started talking about dates, battles and rulers, I felt lost. It all seemed so boring and distant from my reality. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t perceive the value of that knowledge: why on earth would I be interested in what had happened centuries ago?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Over the years, however, something changed. I began to realize my gaps, feeling ashamed of how little I knew about our past (not with others but with myself). I understood that ignoring history was not only an academic shortcoming, but a real limitation in understanding the world around me.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>repetition is the mother of all skills</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/02_thought/repetition/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/02_thought/repetition/</guid><description>&lt;p>There’s a timeless truth in the saying, &lt;em>“Repetition is the mother of all skills.”&lt;/em> It’s something I’ve come to embrace fully since I integrated a method that has completely transformed the way I learn and internalize concepts: &lt;strong>the immersion method&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="what-is-the-immersion-method">What is the Immersion Method?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The immersion method is exactly what it sounds like—a full, deep dive into the subject or skill you want to master. Instead of just skimming the surface or approaching learning sporadically, immersion means surrounding yourself with the material, over and over again, until it becomes second nature. It’s not just about repetition but also about consistency and engagement.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Atomic Habits | James Clear</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/06_books/atomic-habits/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:31:32 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/06_books/atomic-habits/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Atomic Habits&amp;rdquo; by James Clear is an enlightening book that addresses the importance of habits in our daily lives. In a clear and accessible style, the author guides us through the cycle of habits, explaining how they influence our behavior and how we can use them to improve our lives.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="summary-of-the-book">Summary of the Book&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The heart of &amp;ldquo;Atomic Habits&amp;rdquo; is the explanation of how small, seemingly insignificant habits can accumulate over time to produce big results. The book provides a practical structure for building good habits and breaking bad ones, based on four fundamental laws: &lt;strong>Cue, Craving, Response and Reward&lt;/strong>. These elements make up the cycle of habits, a psychological process that determines our behavior.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cars</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/05_passions/car/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:31:32 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/05_passions/car/</guid><description>&lt;p>Fueled by passion and the unforgettable roar of petrol engines, this blog is a tribute to the timeless allure of cars. From a young age, I was mesmerized by the hum of engines, the thrill of watching cars fly by on the road, and the unmistakable connection I felt with each machine. Here, I dive into everything that makes cars more than just vehicles—from the technical finesse of engineering to the pure adrenaline sparked by the sound of a finely-tuned engine. Join me as I explore the art, performance, and culture of cars, where every drive feels like a shared heartbeat between driver and machine.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Guadagna con la mente |</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/06_books/mente-guadagna/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:31:32 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/06_books/mente-guadagna/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="comming-soon-still-reading">COMMING SOON, Still Reading&lt;/h1></description></item><item><title>guida ai bias cognitivi, Capire le Trappole della Mente | Raffaele Gaito</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/06_books/bias-cognitivi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:31:32 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/06_books/bias-cognitivi/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The &lt;em>Cognitive Bias Guide&lt;/em> is a book that helps us discover and understand the mechanisms that influence our thinking and decisions. Cognitive biases are systematic errors that we all make in reasoning, often without realizing it. This book offers practical examples and ideas to recognize and address these mental traps, allowing us to improve our decision-making process.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="book-summary">Book Summary&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The &lt;em>Cognitive Bias Guide&lt;/em> explores how our mind simplifies reality to save energy, but at the cost of introducing distortions in reasoning. It explains why cognitive biases develop and how they affect different aspects of our lives, from everyday choices to important decisions. Among the biases covered, we find:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>ignorance nowadays is a choice</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/02_thought/ignorance-today/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:31:32 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/02_thought/ignorance-today/</guid><description>&lt;p>In the past, access to knowledge was a privilege. Books were scarce, universities were reserved for the elite, and expertise often required access to specialized mentors or tools. But today, the story is completely different. We live in an era where the barriers to learning have all but disappeared, thanks to the transformative power of technology.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-gift-of-unlimited-access">The Gift of Unlimited Access&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The internet, smartphones, and countless platforms like YouTube, Coursera, Udemy, and even Wikipedia have democratized information. Want to master photography? There&amp;rsquo;s a free tutorial for that. Fascinated by astrophysics? Enroll in an online course taught by a renowned professor. Curious about coding? Interactive coding platforms and forums can turn you into a developer from the comfort of your home.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>il grifone | Nicola Gratteri</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/06_books/gratteri/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:31:32 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/06_books/gratteri/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Il Grifone&lt;/em>, written by Nicola Gratteri, is a work that goes beyond the simple narration of the fight against organized crime. This book represents a true manifesto of dedication to justice, embodied by the author himself. Gratteri, magistrate and symbol of the fight against the &amp;rsquo;ndrangheta, dedicates every moment of his life to this mission, sacrificing his personal time and the comforts that his position could guarantee him (a characteristic that fascinates me a lot).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>il vento contro | Daniele Cassioli</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/06_books/cassioli-cuore-a-vedere/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:31:32 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/06_books/cassioli-cuore-a-vedere/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction-the-power-to-transform-adversity-into-opportunity">Introduction, The Power to Transform Adversity into Opportunity&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Il Vento Contro&lt;/em> by Daniele Cassioli is a book about resilience, courage and the ability to see life&amp;rsquo;s challenges as opportunities to grow. Cassioli, a Paralympic athlete who has been blind since birth, is an extraordinary example of how it is possible to overcome the limits imposed by circumstances and live a full and meaningful life. The book is a journey through personal experiences, reflections and lessons that inspire anyone who reads it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>insegna al cuore a vedere | Daniele Cassioli</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/06_books/cassioli-ventro-contro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:31:32 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/06_books/cassioli-ventro-contro/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="comming-soon-still-reading">COMMING SOON, Still Reading&lt;/h1></description></item><item><title>Life Appreciation</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/02_thought/gratitude/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:31:32 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/02_thought/gratitude/</guid><description>&lt;p>We often live in a rush, projected towards new goals and expectations. In this vortex, we can take for granted what we have: our health, our family, the people who love us, or even the simple warmth of the sun on our skin. Yet, when we learn to stop and really “see” these things, we discover a source of serenity and strength that can change our way of living.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-beauty-of-everyday-life">&lt;strong>The Beauty of Everyday Life&lt;/strong>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Being grateful does not only mean recognizing great achievements or resounding successes, but also stopping to observe what surrounds us. It may seem trivial, but appreciating a morning coffee, a sincere smile, or the hug of a dear friend has immense value. These moments remind us that happiness does not lie in great events, but in the sum of many small moments lived with awareness.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Motorbikes</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/05_passions/motorbike/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:31:32 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/05_passions/motorbike/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/01_home/simone-mattioli/05_passions/motorbike/fantic.jpg" alt="My Fantic 50 Motard">
Born from a lifelong craving for the thrill of two wheels, this blog captures the essence of my journey into the world of motorbikes. Ever since I was young, I dreamt of owning my own bike, and when I finally got my Fantic 50 2-stroke, it was everything I’d imagined—and more. From personalizing it to make it uniquely mine, to mastering the art of riding on one wheel, every ride brought a rush of freedom and exhilaration. Here, I’ll share stories, tips, and insights into the motorbike lifestyle, celebrating the pure adrenaline, skill, and connection that only bikers understand. Whether you’re a seasoned rider or just curious, join me on the ride!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mountain bike</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/05_passions/bike/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:31:32 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/05_passions/bike/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/01_home/simone-mattioli/05_passions/bike/mountainbike.jpg" alt="Me exploring the beauty of Rabbi Valley">
This blog is all about the adrenaline, freedom, and connection with nature that mountain biking has brought into my life. Ever since my first ride, I was hooked—there’s nothing like the thrill of hitting rugged trails, mastering new terrain, and feeling the rush of carving through mountainsides.
From discovering the best gear and customizing my setup to push my limits, to the pure satisfaction of conquering new trails, mountain biking has become more than a sport—it’s a passion. Here, I’ll share tips, personal stories, trail reviews, and everything that makes mountain biking an adventure worth chasing. Whether you’re a seasoned rider or a curious beginner, join me in exploring the world on two wheels!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mountain Hiking</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/05_passions/hiking/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:31:32 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/05_passions/hiking/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="-comming-soon"># comming soon&amp;hellip;&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/01_home/simone-mattioli/05_passions/hiking/sfondo.JPG" alt="">
&lt;img src="https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/01_home/simone-mattioli/05_passions/hiking/alba.JPG" alt="">
&lt;img src="https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/01_home/simone-mattioli/05_passions/hiking/rabb.JPG" alt="">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pensieri lenti pensieri veloci</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/06_books/pensieri-lenti-pensieri-veloci/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:31:32 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/06_books/pensieri-lenti-pensieri-veloci/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="comming-soon-still-reading">COMMING SOON, Still Reading&lt;/h1></description></item><item><title>Personal Growth</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/05_passions/persona-growth/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:31:32 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/05_passions/persona-growth/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/01_home/simone-mattioli/05_passions/persona-growth/personalgrowth.jpg" alt="as">
Embark on a journey of &lt;strong>personal growth&lt;/strong> and self-discovery! This blog is all about transforming life, one article, one book, and one action at a time. Starting with a simple curiosity, I dove into the world of personal development, reading about habits, resilience, mindfulness, and purpose. Each insight led to real changes in how I see myself, set goals, and make decisions. Here, I’ll share lessons from books and articles that have had the biggest impact on my life, along with actionable tips and reflections on the changes I’ve experienced. Join me in exploring the power of intentional self-improvement and see how small shifts can lead to profound personal transformation&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Rich and Poor Dad | Robert Kiyosaki</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/06_books/grow-rich/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:31:32 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/06_books/grow-rich/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="rich-dad-poor-dad-personal-finance-for-everyone">Rich Dad Poor Dad: Personal Finance for Everyone?&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Rich Dad Poor Dad&lt;/em> by Robert Kiyosaki is one of the most popular books in the world of personal finance. First published in 1997, it chronicles the lessons the author learned from two father figures: “Rich Dad” (the father of a friend who is a successful entrepreneur) and “Poor Dad” (Kiyosaki’s biological father who is educated but stuck in an employee mentality). The book aims to teach money management and investing principles, emphasizing the importance of changing one’s approach to wealth.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ski</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/05_passions/ski/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:31:32 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/05_passions/ski/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="comming-soon">comming soon&amp;hellip;&lt;/h1></description></item><item><title>The 20th century Trap</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/02_thought/trap/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:31:32 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/02_thought/trap/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="detached-from-stimuli">Detached from stimuli&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>We live in an age of constant stimulation, a constant flow of notifications, updates and digital content that keep us constantly &amp;ldquo;connected&amp;rdquo; but, at the same time, drastically reduce our ability to concentrate. Every day, we are bombarded with visual and auditory stimuli through social media, messaging apps, entertainment platforms, which now guide our lives both online and offline.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-loss-of-attention-span">The Loss of Attention Span&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This situation scares me. I have noticed, especially during the pandemic, how much social media has taken on the role of &amp;ldquo;directors&amp;rdquo; of our lives. People talk about news, trends, and aspects of other people&amp;rsquo;s lives that they have learned on social media, as if these have replaced real experiences. Our attention span has reduced to almost absurd levels: we are incapable of standing in line or waiting without taking out our phones in search of new stimuli. This constant search for instant gratification through digital devices deprives us of the ability to fully live in the moment.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>think and grow rich | Napoleon Hill</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/06_books/think/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:31:32 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/06_books/think/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction-to-napoleon-hills-philosophy-of-success">Introduction to Napoleon Hill&amp;rsquo;s Philosophy of Success&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Think and Grow Rich&lt;/em> by Napoleon Hill is an evergreen in personal development and success. First published in 1937, it is a practical guide that teaches how positive thinking, determination and a clear vision of goals can transform dreams into reality. Hill has studied the lives of great successful men, such as Andrew Carnegie, Henry Ford and Thomas Edison, for over 25 years and has distilled their secrets into this timeless masterpiece.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Who's Simone Mattioli ?</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/01_home/simone-mattioli/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:31:32 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/01_home/simone-mattioli/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="personal-life">Personal Life&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="early-days">Early Days&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/01_home/simone-mattioli/01_home/simone-mattioli/rabbi.JPG" alt="Me when I was a child in Val di Rabbi">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was born in the little town of Rovereto, on 28 July 2003 in Italy, nestled in Trentino-Alto Adige, Italy. Since my earliest years, I’ve been passionate about technology, vehicles, and sports that fuel my curiosity, drive, and creativity.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="the-context">The context&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/01_home/simone-mattioli/01_home/simone-mattioli/biking.JPG" alt="Me super happy with my first mountain bike">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Growing up surrounded by the natural beauty and rich culture of Northern Italy, I found myself drawn to the mechanics of how things work, from engines to computers. My passion for technology started young and has only grown over the years, inspiring me to learn and explore more every day.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Birdwatching Experience with SWAROVSKI OPTIK at Le Ali del Frassino Residence (Lake Frassino)</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/04_experiences/frassino/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/04_experiences/frassino/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/01_home/simone-mattioli/04_experiences/frassino/swarovski.jpeg" alt="Logo Swarovski Optik">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recently, thanks to my project &lt;em>Mountain Fauna Lover&lt;/em>, I had the chance to participate in an exclusive event organized by SWAROVSKI OPTIK Italy at the stunning Frassino Oasis in Peschiera del Garda.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Mountain Fauna Lover&lt;/em> began almost as a joke, born from my love for mountains and wildlife. I never imagined it would open doors to such exciting collaborations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/01_home/simone-mattioli/04_experiences/frassino/migrazione.jpg" alt="Bird Migration">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Through this project, I’ve been able to experience nature up close, often alongside experts and using top-tier equipment, making each adventure more unforgettable than the last.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Don Mazza College</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/04_experiences/mazza/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/04_experiences/mazza/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Spiegare come l&amp;rsquo;ho trovato&lt;/li>
&lt;li>come mi sono trovato&lt;/li>
&lt;li>linkare il mio video &amp;ldquo;recensione&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Esperienze fatte:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>conoscenza di persone ( poche, 1 -&amp;gt; Vale )&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Condivisione&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Ore formative&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Viaggio di Budapest&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Confronto con gli altri coetanei&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>EPICURE Hackathon GPU - October 2024</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/03_projects/epicure-hackathon-2024/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/03_projects/epicure-hackathon-2024/</guid><description>&lt;p>The &lt;strong>EPICURE Hackathon&lt;/strong>, held from October 28-31, 2024, brought together developers, researchers, and enthusiasts from across Europe to dive deep into the world of &lt;strong>GPU programming and high-performance computing (HPC)&lt;/strong>. This event was hosted in collaboration with &lt;strong>CINECA&lt;/strong>, one of the leading HPC centers in Europe, renowned for its contributions to scientific computing and advanced research.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The hackathon was meticulously structured, featuring both hands-on labs and theoretical sessions, designed to empower participants with the latest skills in &lt;strong>CUDA programming&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>OpenACC&lt;/strong>, and &lt;strong>GPU optimization techniques&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Volounteering Activity in Brazil</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/04_experiences/brazil/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/04_experiences/brazil/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/01_home/simone-mattioli/04_experiences/brazil/don-mazza-pia.jpg" alt="Don Mazza Logo">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My volunteer experience in Brazil was an unforgettable journey that led me to discover not only a country rich in culture, but also the daily challenges faced by people in vulnerable situations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We left in seven, a heterogeneous group composed of six strangers from different Italian cities: Verona, Padua and Rome. The experience was organized by &lt;strong>Collegio Di Merito Don Mazza&lt;/strong>, an institution that promotes social commitment and volunteering as well as providing accommodation for university students.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>21th birth Day in Brazil</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/04_experiences/21th-birthday/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/04_experiences/21th-birthday/</guid><description>&lt;p>My 21st birthday was unique, an experience I will never forget. I spent it in Brazil, during my volunteering period, far from home and all my loved ones. On that occasion, I was not surrounded by the familiar faces of friends and relatives, but by six strangers, who shared with me the experience of volunteering in a country so different from mine.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/01_home/simone-mattioli/04_experiences/21th-birthday/spiaggia.png" alt="Relaxing morning in Olinda beach">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I did not expect anything special. Usually, birthdays have never had a particular meaning for me, but that day turned out to be different, special, unique. Celebrating a birthday far from home and loved ones was a first step out of my comfort zone. It allowed me to live the moment with lightness and curiosity, immersed in a new experience.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mountain Fauna Lover</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/03_projects/mountain-fauna-lover/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/03_projects/mountain-fauna-lover/</guid><description>&lt;p>Welcome to MountainFaunaLover! Here, I share my passion for nature, wildlife, and the captivating landscapes of mountain regions. On Instagram, you’ll find a curated collection of my favorite moments in the wilderness, from up-close shots of unique wildlife to breathtaking mountain vistas. Each post is a window into my adventures, capturing the serenity, beauty, and diversity of the natural world that inspires me daily.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On YouTube, I dive even deeper. My channel is a space for storytelling, featuring video journeys, wildlife encounters, and conservation insights, bringing viewers along on my explorations. Whether you’re a fellow nature enthusiast or just stopping by for some visual serenity, my content on MountainFaunaLover is dedicated to sharing the awe and importance of our wild places. Join me in celebrating the mountains, fauna, and the fascinating stories they hold!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Simo Performance Coach Consultant</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/03_projects/performance/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/03_projects/performance/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="stay-tunedmore-info-are-comming-soon-meanwhile-you-can-contact-me-via-email-for-info">STAY TUNED&amp;hellip;more info are comming soon, meanwhile you can contact me via email for INFO&lt;/h2></description></item><item><title>Simo's Online &amp; Digital Diary</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/03_projects/home/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/03_projects/home/</guid><description>&lt;p>Welcome to simo&amp;rsquo;s Diary, a place where I love to share&amp;hellip;.da completare&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="discover-my-youtube-channel-simos-diary">Discover My YouTube Channel: Simo&amp;rsquo;s Diary&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Today I want to tell you about my YouTube channel, &lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/@SimosDiary2003">Simo&amp;rsquo;s Diary&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>, where I share moments of my life, personal projects and passions. This space was born from the desire to document my experiences in an authentic and transparent way, showing you trips, adventures and much more.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="why-did-i-create-simos-diary">Why Did I Create Simo&amp;rsquo;s Diary?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We live in an era where technology allows us to capture moments in high quality simply with a smartphone. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to waste this opportunity! In fact, I think it&amp;rsquo;s fantastic to be able to record and share pieces of my life that, otherwise, would only remain in memory. With Simo&amp;rsquo;s Diary, not only can I collect these memories for the future, but also share them with anyone who wants to follow them and maybe find inspiration.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Search</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/search/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/01_home/simone-mattioli/search/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>