<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gratitude on Simone Mattioli</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/gratitude.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Gratitude on Simone Mattioli</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:31:32 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/gratitude/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>ignorance nowadays is a choice</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/02_thought/ignorance-today.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:31:32 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/02_thought/ignorance-today.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the past, access to knowledge was a privilege. Books were scarce, universities were reserved for the elite, and expertise often required access to specialized mentors or tools. But today, the story is completely different. We live in an era where the barriers to learning have all but disappeared, thanks to the transformative power of technology.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-gift-of-unlimited-access&#34;&gt;The Gift of Unlimited Access&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The internet, smartphones, and countless platforms like YouTube, Coursera, Udemy, and even Wikipedia have democratized information. Want to master photography? There&amp;rsquo;s a free tutorial for that. Fascinated by astrophysics? Enroll in an online course taught by a renowned professor. Curious about coding? Interactive coding platforms and forums can turn you into a developer from the comfort of your home.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Life Appreciation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/02_thought/gratitude.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:31:32 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/02_thought/gratitude.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We often live in a rush, projected towards new goals and expectations. In this vortex, we can take for granted what we have: our health, our family, the people who love us, or even the simple warmth of the sun on our skin. Yet, when we learn to stop and really “see” these things, we discover a source of serenity and strength that can change our way of living.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-beauty-of-everyday-life&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Beauty of Everyday Life&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Being grateful does not only mean recognizing great achievements or resounding successes, but also stopping to observe what surrounds us. It may seem trivial, but appreciating a morning coffee, a sincere smile, or the hug of a dear friend has immense value. These moments remind us that happiness does not lie in great events, but in the sum of many small moments lived with awareness.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
