<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Books on Simone Mattioli</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/categories/books.html</link><description>Recent content in Books on Simone Mattioli</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:31:32 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://simo-hue.github.io/categories/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Atomic Habits | James Clear</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/06_books/atomic-habits.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:31:32 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/06_books/atomic-habits.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Atomic Habits&amp;rdquo; by James Clear is an enlightening book that addresses the importance of habits in our daily lives. In a clear and accessible style, the author guides us through the cycle of habits, explaining how they influence our behavior and how we can use them to improve our lives.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="summary-of-the-book">Summary of the Book&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The heart of &amp;ldquo;Atomic Habits&amp;rdquo; is the explanation of how small, seemingly insignificant habits can accumulate over time to produce big results. The book provides a practical structure for building good habits and breaking bad ones, based on four fundamental laws: &lt;strong>Cue, Craving, Response and Reward&lt;/strong>. These elements make up the cycle of habits, a psychological process that determines our behavior.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Guadagna con la mente |</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/06_books/mente-guadagna.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:31:32 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/06_books/mente-guadagna.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="comming-soon-still-reading">COMMING SOON, Still Reading&lt;/h1></description></item><item><title>guida ai bias cognitivi, Capire le Trappole della Mente | Raffaele Gaito</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/06_books/bias-cognitivi.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:31:32 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/06_books/bias-cognitivi.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The &lt;em>Cognitive Bias Guide&lt;/em> is a book that helps us discover and understand the mechanisms that influence our thinking and decisions. Cognitive biases are systematic errors that we all make in reasoning, often without realizing it. This book offers practical examples and ideas to recognize and address these mental traps, allowing us to improve our decision-making process.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="book-summary">Book Summary&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The &lt;em>Cognitive Bias Guide&lt;/em> explores how our mind simplifies reality to save energy, but at the cost of introducing distortions in reasoning. It explains why cognitive biases develop and how they affect different aspects of our lives, from everyday choices to important decisions. Among the biases covered, we find:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>il grifone | Nicola Gratteri</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/06_books/gratteri.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:31:32 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/06_books/gratteri.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Il Grifone&lt;/em>, written by Nicola Gratteri, is a work that goes beyond the simple narration of the fight against organized crime. This book represents a true manifesto of dedication to justice, embodied by the author himself. Gratteri, magistrate and symbol of the fight against the &amp;rsquo;ndrangheta, dedicates every moment of his life to this mission, sacrificing his personal time and the comforts that his position could guarantee him (a characteristic that fascinates me a lot).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>il vento contro | Daniele Cassioli</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/06_books/cassioli-cuore-a-vedere.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:31:32 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/06_books/cassioli-cuore-a-vedere.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction-the-power-to-transform-adversity-into-opportunity">Introduction, The Power to Transform Adversity into Opportunity&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Il Vento Contro&lt;/em> by Daniele Cassioli is a book about resilience, courage and the ability to see life&amp;rsquo;s challenges as opportunities to grow. Cassioli, a Paralympic athlete who has been blind since birth, is an extraordinary example of how it is possible to overcome the limits imposed by circumstances and live a full and meaningful life. The book is a journey through personal experiences, reflections and lessons that inspire anyone who reads it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>insegna al cuore a vedere | Daniele Cassioli</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/06_books/cassioli-ventro-contro.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:31:32 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/06_books/cassioli-ventro-contro.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="comming-soon-still-reading">COMMING SOON, Still Reading&lt;/h1></description></item><item><title>Pensieri lenti pensieri veloci</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/06_books/pensieri-lenti-pensieri-veloci.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:31:32 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/06_books/pensieri-lenti-pensieri-veloci.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="comming-soon-still-reading">COMMING SOON, Still Reading&lt;/h1></description></item><item><title>Rich and Poor Dad | Robert Kiyosaki</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/06_books/grow-rich.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:31:32 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/06_books/grow-rich.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="rich-dad-poor-dad-personal-finance-for-everyone">Rich Dad Poor Dad: Personal Finance for Everyone?&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Rich Dad Poor Dad&lt;/em> by Robert Kiyosaki is one of the most popular books in the world of personal finance. First published in 1997, it chronicles the lessons the author learned from two father figures: “Rich Dad” (the father of a friend who is a successful entrepreneur) and “Poor Dad” (Kiyosaki’s biological father who is educated but stuck in an employee mentality). The book aims to teach money management and investing principles, emphasizing the importance of changing one’s approach to wealth.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>think and grow rich | Napoleon Hill</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/06_books/think.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:31:32 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/06_books/think.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction-to-napoleon-hills-philosophy-of-success">Introduction to Napoleon Hill&amp;rsquo;s Philosophy of Success&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Think and Grow Rich&lt;/em> by Napoleon Hill is an evergreen in personal development and success. First published in 1937, it is a practical guide that teaches how positive thinking, determination and a clear vision of goals can transform dreams into reality. Hill has studied the lives of great successful men, such as Andrew Carnegie, Henry Ford and Thomas Edison, for over 25 years and has distilled their secrets into this timeless masterpiece.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>