<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Experiences on Simone Mattioli</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/04_experiences.html</link><description>Recent content in Experiences on Simone Mattioli</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://simo-hue.github.io/04_experiences/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>NO MAFIA, Sicily Tour with LIA Rovereto</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/04_experiences/sicily.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/04_experiences/sicily.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Birdwatching Experience with SWAROVSKI OPTIK at Le Ali del Frassino Residence (Lake Frassino)</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/04_experiences/swarovski-optik-le-ali-del-frassino.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/04_experiences/swarovski-optik-le-ali-del-frassino.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img alt="Logo Swarovski Optik" src="https://simo-hue.github.io/04_experiences/swarovski-optik-le-ali-del-frassino/swarovski.jpeg">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recently, thanks to my project &lt;em>Mountain Fauna Lover&lt;/em>, I had the chance to participate in an exclusive event organized by SWAROVSKI OPTIK Italy at the stunning Frassino Oasis in Peschiera del Garda.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Mountain Fauna Lover&lt;/em> began almost as a joke, born from my love for mountains and wildlife. I never imagined it would open doors to such exciting collaborations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img alt="Bird Migration" src="https://simo-hue.github.io/04_experiences/swarovski-optik-le-ali-del-frassino/migrazione.jpg">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Through this project, I’ve been able to experience nature up close, often alongside experts and using top-tier equipment, making each adventure more unforgettable than the last.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Volounteering Activity in Brazil</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/04_experiences/volounteering-activity-in-brazil.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/04_experiences/volounteering-activity-in-brazil.html</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;img alt="Don Mazza Logo" src="https://simo-hue.github.io/04_experiences/volounteering-activity-in-brazil/don-mazza-pia.jpg">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My volunteer experience in Brazil was an unforgettable journey that led me to discover not only a country rich in culture, but also the daily challenges faced by people in vulnerable situations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We left in seven, a heterogeneous group composed of six strangers from different Italian cities: Verona, Padua and Rome. The experience was organized by &lt;strong>Collegio Di Merito Don Mazza&lt;/strong>, an institution that promotes social commitment and volunteering as well as providing accommodation for university students.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>21th birth Day in Brazil</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/04_experiences/21th-birthday.html</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/04_experiences/21th-birthday.html</guid><description>&lt;p>My 21st birthday was unique, an experience I will never forget. I spent it in Brazil, during my volunteering period, far from home and all my loved ones. On that occasion, I was not surrounded by the familiar faces of friends and relatives, but by six strangers, who shared with me the experience of volunteering in a country so different from mine.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img alt="Relaxing morning in Olinda beach" src="https://simo-hue.github.io/04_experiences/21th-birthday/spiaggia.png">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I did not expect anything special. Usually, birthdays have never had a particular meaning for me, but that day turned out to be different, special, unique. Celebrating a birthday far from home and loved ones was a first step out of my comfort zone. It allowed me to live the moment with lightness and curiosity, immersed in a new experience.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>