<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Home on Simone Mattioli</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Home on Simone Mattioli</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 14:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Inizio progetto di laurea</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/news/2025-05-20-progetto-tesi/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 14:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/news/2025-05-20-progetto-tesi/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Qui i dettagli…&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Machina Sapiens | Nello Cristianini</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/06_books/machina-sapiens/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 19:31:32 +0100</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/06_books/machina-sapiens/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/06_books/machina-sapiens/image.png" alt="Featured image of post Machina Sapiens | Nello Cristianini" /&gt;&lt;h1 id=&#34;reflections-on-a-visionary-book&#34;&gt;Reflections on a Visionary Book
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;I recently finished reading the book &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Machina Sapiens&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt; by Nello Cristianini, an author I deeply admire for his expertise and ability to make complex topics related to artificial intelligence accessible. This book is not only an exploration of emerging technologies, but also a philosophical journey that fascinated me and, I must admit, a little scared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-summary-of-the-book&#34;&gt;A Summary of the Book
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Machina Sapiens&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; is a brilliant and provocative investigation into the ethical, social and philosophical implications of the development of artificial intelligence. Cristianini guides us through the roots of the discipline, starting from the visions of Alan Turing and arriving at modern machine learning technologies. The book analyzes how machines are progressively &amp;ldquo;learning&amp;rdquo; to make decisions in ways that we cannot always understand or control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among the central themes we find:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The emergence of algorithms capable of influencing society.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The challenges of living with non-human intelligences.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The ethical questions we must face in this new scenario.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cristianini warns on a fundamental point: &lt;strong&gt;machines do not think, but calculate. Yet, their ability to influence our world grows every day.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most powerful sentences in the book, which struck me deeply, is this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;The only weapon against the unknown and fear is knowledge.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-7-most-important-lessons-learned&#34;&gt;The 7 Most Important Lessons Learned
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The neutrality of algorithms is a myth&lt;/strong&gt;
Algorithms are never truly neutral. They reflect the biases and decisions of the humans who designed them, often amplifying them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The importance of critical understanding&lt;/strong&gt;
We can no longer afford to ignore how the technologies that influence our lives work. Understanding is the first step to managing their implications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The risk of losing control&lt;/strong&gt;
Once systems become too complex, even their creators struggle to understand them. The risk is not that machines will become “conscious,” but that they will act in unpredictable ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alan Turing’s legacy is coming true&lt;/strong&gt;
Turing’s predictions, such as the possibility of creating machines that simulate human thought, are gradually coming true. It is disturbing to see how many of his fears are taking shape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technology is not intrinsically good or bad&lt;/strong&gt;
It is how we use it that determines its impact. We need to develop greater ethical awareness in designing and using AI systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The power of information&lt;/strong&gt;
The ability to collect, analyze and use huge amounts of data is both an opportunity and a threat. Information is power, and controlling it can be dangerous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Knowledge is our defense&lt;/strong&gt;
To address the fears and uncertainties related to artificial intelligence, we must educate and prepare ourselves. Only through knowledge can we navigate safely into the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-reflections&#34;&gt;My Reflections
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have to admit that this book left me with a sense of uneasiness. Cristianini&amp;rsquo;s descriptions of the capabilities of machines and their impact on the world made me think about how quickly we are advancing towards a future that seems more and more similar to Alan Turing&amp;rsquo;s predictions. Yet, there is also a note of hope: &lt;strong&gt;we still have the power to shape our future, as long as we choose knowledge and awareness.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-quote-to-reflect-on&#34;&gt;A Quote to Reflect On
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I close with a quote that represents the heart of Cristianini&amp;rsquo;s message:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Machines do not think. We do. And it is our responsibility to always do so, even when we entrust them with tasks that seem trivial.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book taught me that, if we want to coexist with &amp;ldquo;machine sapiens&amp;rdquo;, we must first learn to know ourselves and the potential of our creations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I invite you to read &amp;ldquo;Machina Sapiens&amp;rdquo; to explore these issues in depth and share your reflections! But above all also to NOT be caught unprepared for this revolution that is happening&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Wheelchair Basketball</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/basket-in-carrozzina/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/basket-in-carrozzina/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/basket-in-carrozzina/home.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Wheelchair Basketball" /&gt;&lt;h1 id=&#34;an-experience-that-changes-your-perspective-wheelchair-basketball&#34;&gt;An Experience That Changes Your Perspective: Wheelchair Basketball
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the extraordinary collaboration between &lt;strong&gt;Collegio Don Mazza&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Residenza Ferrari delle Spade di Verona&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Olympic Basket Verona&lt;/strong&gt;, I had the opportunity to live one of the most significant experiences of my life: trying &lt;strong&gt;wheelchair basketball&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/basket-in-carrozzina/me.jpeg&#34;
	width=&#34;1290&#34;
	height=&#34;2271&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/basket-in-carrozzina/me_hu7327529814731187994.jpeg 480w, http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/basket-in-carrozzina/me_hu10911303650925941073.jpeg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;This is Me having fun trying this new unbelivable sport&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;56&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;136px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-unique-experience&#34;&gt;A unique experience
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This discipline goes far beyond a simple game. It is a real lesson in strength, determination and inclusion. Sitting in a wheelchair, picking up the ball and trying to move, shoot and collaborate with the rest of the team was enlightening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I learned that sport is a universal language, capable of breaking down all types of barriers – physical, mental and cultural. It was an opportunity to see the world from a completely different perspective, to recognize the daily challenges that many athletes face and to appreciate their commitment and resilience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sport-as-a-driver-of-inspiration&#34;&gt;Sport as a driver of inspiration
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;As Nelson Mandela said:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Sport has the power to change the world. It has the power to inspire. It has the power to unite people like few other things in the world.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is exactly what I felt during this experience. Sport is a powerful tool to overcome limits and to build authentic bonds with those around us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another phrase that strongly resonates with this experience is that of John Wooden:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Don’t let what you can’t do get in the way of what you can do.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wheelchair basketball shows that with passion, determination and team spirit there are no insurmountable obstacles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;olympic-basket-verona-a-reality-to-discover&#34;&gt;Olympic Basket Verona: a reality to discover
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;A special thanks goes to &lt;strong&gt;Olympic Basket Verona&lt;/strong&gt;, a reality that represents a true example of inclusion and promotion of sport for all. If you want to know more about them, here&amp;rsquo;s where you can find them online:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Facebook&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/OlympicVerona/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Olympic Basket Verona&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Instagram&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/olympic_basket_verona/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;@olympic_basket_verona&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;watch-the-video-of-my-experience&#34;&gt;Watch the video of my experience
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you want to immerse yourself in this unique experience, take a look at the video I made:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video-wrapper&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
            src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/T7m9n7ojHzw&#34; 
            allowfullscreen 
            title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;
    &gt;
    &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;💡 &lt;strong&gt;And you? Have you ever had an experience that helped you change your perspective?&lt;/strong&gt; Tell me in the comments or contact me directly, I&amp;rsquo;d love to hear your story!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;hashtags-for-sharing&#34;&gt;Hashtags for sharing
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;#Inclusion #WheelchairBasketball #SportForAll #Determination #Resilience #BreakingBarriers #Teamwork #Inspiration #OlympicBasketVerona&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Relationship Importance</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/02_thought/relationship/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/02_thought/relationship/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/02_thought/relationship/logo.png" alt="Featured image of post Relationship Importance" /&gt;&lt;h1 id=&#34;friendship-and-love&#34;&gt;Friendship and Love
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Human relationships are the fundamental pillar of our existence, it is no coincidence that it is said that man is a social animal&amp;hellip; Friendships, family ties and romantic relationships contribute to defining not only the quality of our life, but also who we are and what we can become. We cannot ignore the enormous impact that these connections have on us, for better or for worse, and on our lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;dont-settle-aim-for-the-1&#34;&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t settle: Aim for the 1%
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;We live in a world where too many people settle. The fear of loneliness pushes many to build relationships that do not enrich, but limit. This attitude is unacceptable in my opinion. The quality of the people you choose to have in your life can make the difference between a full life and a mediocre one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Jim Rohn said:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You are the average of the five people you hang out with the most.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surrounding yourself with the right people doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean finding just anyone, but looking for that tiny 1% that inspires you, pushes you to grow, supports you in challenges and motivates you to become the best version of yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;friendship-the-value-of-sincere-support&#34;&gt;Friendship: The value of sincere support
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;A true friend is not just a companion for laughter, but also a partner in personal growth and the support you know you can count on in the darkest and most difficult moments. The best friends are those who are not afraid to confront you with your mistakes, to encourage you when necessary and to celebrate your successes with you. Choosing friends who share your values ​​and aspirations is not always easy, but it is &lt;em&gt;essential&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Seneca said:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“A friend is someone who wants for you what he wants for himself.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be careful who you trust. Not everyone who seems like a friend is really one, and not everyone has the courage or the ability to support you in times of need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;love-relationships-building-not-limiting&#34;&gt;Love Relationships: Building, Not Limiting
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Choosing a partner is perhaps one of the most important decisions in our lives. The person you choose to share your time and emotions with has the power to determine your destiny. A healthy and authentic relationship is one that enriches you, pushes you to new heights, and creates a safe space for your personal development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Friedrich Nietzsche wrote:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It is not the lack of love, but the lack of friendship that makes marriages unhappy.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t settle for someone just because you’re afraid of being alone. Have the courage to wait for that person who not only completes your life, but elevates it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion-choose-wisely&#34;&gt;Conclusion: Choose Wisely
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Life is too short to waste it on the wrong people. Every relationship you choose should be a conscious choice, not a fallback. Surround yourself with people who challenge you to be better, who support you in difficult times, and who share your vision of life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take the time to think about who you want in your circle. It’s not easy, but it’s one of the most important decisions you can make. As Aristotle said:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“In poverty and other adversities of life, true friends are a safe refuge. The young who love and the old who are loved are the greatest comforts we can have.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember: It’s not just about company, it’s about quality. Choose the 1% in all areas of your life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/02_thought/relationship/fa.webp&#34;
	width=&#34;1792&#34;
	height=&#34;1024&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/02_thought/relationship/fa_hu3615225901214082683.webp 480w, http://localhost:1313/02_thought/relationship/fa_hu8395372992921575595.webp 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Remember To Dream Big&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;175&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;420px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>NO MAFIA Sicily Tour</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/sicily/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/sicily/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/sicily/home.png" alt="Featured image of post NO MAFIA Sicily Tour" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;tour sicilia, da implementare&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TO DO:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;passarsi tutte le foto orizzontali&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fare table di tutte le cose che abbiamo fatto&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;premesse &amp;amp; aspettative&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contesto storico&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stazione di capaci&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;buncherino&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;palermo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Segno della resistenza sulla scrivania di Borsellino -&amp;gt; ( l&amp;rsquo;ho interpretato come ) la resistenza e resilienza che ogni essere umano ( Di successo ) deve avere&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;determinazione che ci vuole per raggiungere grandi cose&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;testimonianza del fotografo ( magari nei thought  mettere che siamo una generazione che si smagnetizzerà -&amp;gt; problema del digitale )&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Come vogliono rappresentare la loro terra ( senso di appartenenza / eliminazione degli stereotipi)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;La differenza tra una guida &amp;ldquo;normale&amp;rdquo; del 99% ed il top 1% ( come in ogni settore si può eccellere e non)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video-wrapper&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
            src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/RdgWMgmqqHk&#34; 
            allowfullscreen 
            title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;
    &gt;
    &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Spread Love wherever you go</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/02_thought/love/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/02_thought/love/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/02_thought/love/image.png" alt="Featured image of post Spread Love wherever you go" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Kindness is one of those little gestures that make days brighter, both for the giver and the receiver. I have always found comfort in being kind to others, even in the simplest actions. A smile, a greeting, a “how are you?” may seem insignificant, but they often have a profound impact. They are small acts that cost nothing, but that bring enormous wealth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like to think that every little kindness is a seed of happiness that spreads around us. From holding a door open for those who follow, to giving a coin to someone in need, to giving a smile to someone in need. These gestures not only make others feel better, but they also fill my heart with joy. And more often than not, I realize that, without even wanting to, I have given a smile to someone else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember with particular affection an episode that happened during a visit to a museum in Palermo. As I was leaving, I greeted the ticket inspector who was near the door. He seemed surprised and thanked me with sincere gratitude. He said, &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;You were the only one who greeted me among those who came out.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; Those words struck a chord with me. It was such a simple gesture, almost automatic for me, but for him it made a difference. It reminded me of how powerful a small kindness can be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, I believe the world needs more love and kindness. We shouldn&amp;rsquo;t expect grand gestures to make a difference; often it&amp;rsquo;s the simplest actions that leave a mark. As Mother Teresa said:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Not all of us can do great things, but we can do small things with great love.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So why not start today? Spread love wherever you go.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The importance of being able to stay alone</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/02_thought/alone/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/02_thought/alone/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/02_thought/alone/alone.png" alt="Featured image of post The importance of being able to stay alone" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Knowing how to be alone is an often underestimated skill, but it is incredibly important for our personal growth. In a world that seems to constantly push us to seek the company of others, taking time for ourselves can be a revolutionary act. Not only does it allow us to know ourselves better, but it can turn into a real training ground for growing as a person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;know-yourself&#34;&gt;Know Yourself
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Solitude is a precious space to get in touch with ourselves. When we are alone, without distractions, we can listen to our thoughts and discover who we really are. What makes us happy? What do we want from life? What are our values? These are questions that we rarely find the time to address, but which can guide us towards a more authentic life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;break-free-from-social-pressure&#34;&gt;Break Free from Social Pressure
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is not normal, nor necessary, to always be surrounded by people. We often feel obliged to be part of groups or situations that do not represent us, just for fear of being judged. Learning to be alone helps us break free from this social pressure. There is nothing wrong with taking time for yourself, saying no to things that don’t make you feel good, and reclaiming your independence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;becoming-independent-and-strong&#34;&gt;Becoming Independent and Strong
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;When we learn to be comfortable alone, we become stronger. We no longer need to constantly lean on others to find security or happiness. This doesn’t mean closing ourselves off from the world, but being independent, knowing that our inner strength is enough to face life’s challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;harnessing-the-value-of-solitude&#34;&gt;Harnessing the Value of Solitude
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Solitude is fertile ground for creativity and reflection. When we give ourselves time to be alone, thoughts and ideas often emerge that we would never have had otherwise. However, these moments must be lived consciously. If we let ourselves be overwhelmed by negative stimuli, such as excessive use of social media, we risk turning solitude into isolation and, in the worst cases, depression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make the most of solitude, we must live it with intention: reading a good book, meditating, walking in nature or simply reflecting on ourselves. These moments can be incredibly regenerating and transformative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;solitude-as-a-gym-for-growth&#34;&gt;Solitude as a Gym for Growth
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Solitude is not an enemy, but an opportunity. It is a space that allows us to grow, to become more aware and to strengthen our independence. As Rainer Maria Rilke wrote:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Solitude is like rain: it rises from the sea towards the evening, from distant and remote plains, it rises to the sky, which always possesses it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taking time for ourselves is a gift we can give ourselves, every day. Don&amp;rsquo;t be afraid of being alone: ​​that&amp;rsquo;s where you could discover the best version of yourself&amp;hellip;but I would also like to remind you that&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not everyone is able to do it, but you must be one of them&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Daniele Cassioli</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/02_thought/cassioli/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/02_thought/cassioli/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/02_thought/cassioli/home.png" alt="Featured image of post Daniele Cassioli" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;I had the privilege of meeting Daniele Cassioli, and I can say that it was a deeply enriching experience. For those who don&amp;rsquo;t know him, Daniele is a blind Paralympic athlete, world champion in water skiing, author and motivational speaker. His story is an extraordinary example of how to transform difficulties into opportunities, and his way of life is a lesson that leads to reflection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;gratitude-for-opportunities&#34;&gt;Gratitude for Opportunities
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Being a student at the Collegio di Merito Don Mazza in Verona is an opportunity that has allowed me to participate in significant events like this. Meetings like this are precious opportunities to grow and look at the world with different eyes. I can only be grateful for everything that this college offers me, not only in terms of training, but also in terms of inspiration and awareness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-daniele-cassioli-foundation&#34;&gt;The Daniele Cassioli Foundation
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Daniele is not only an athlete, but also the founder of an extraordinary reality: the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.danielecassioli.it&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Daniele Cassioli Foundation&lt;/a&gt;. This organization is dedicated to supporting young people with disabilities, helping them discover and develop their potential through sports and educational activities. It is incredible to see how this foundation not only offers opportunities, but also contributes to changing society&amp;rsquo;s mentality towards disability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-deeper-awareness&#34;&gt;A Deeper Awareness
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Meeting Daniele made me reflect on how often, as able-bodied people, we take many things for granted. His story taught me that it is not what we lack that defines who we are, but what we develop to overcome challenges. Daniele has honed extraordinary skills, demonstrating that difficulties can become strengths.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;making-fun-of-ones-flaws&#34;&gt;Making Fun of One&amp;rsquo;s Flaws
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the aspects that struck me most about Daniele is his ability to make fun of his own flaws and misfortunes. This not only makes him incredibly charismatic, but it is also a life lesson: knowing how to laugh at ourselves allows us to live with more serenity and at peace with ourselves. His light-heartedness is contagious and shows that accepting one&amp;rsquo;s limits is the first step to overcoming them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;his-books-and-the-value-of-sport&#34;&gt;His Books and the Value of Sport
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Daniele is also the author of inspirational books. Among these, I read one of his texts and it struck me for the depth of his messages and the simplicity with which he manages to convey complex concepts. Furthermore, during our meeting, he underlined the importance of sport not only for physical health, but also for mental well-being and happiness. Sport is a great life teacher and a way to create authentic bonds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-social-role-of-great-impact&#34;&gt;A Social Role of Great Impact
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Daniele&amp;rsquo;s role in society is fundamental. He helps young people with disabilities to see a brighter future and not give up in the face of difficulties. In a world that tends to put labels, Daniele shows that you can live a full and fulfilling life, transmitting confidence and motivation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-importance-of-community-even-in-individual-sports&#34;&gt;The Importance of Community, Even in Individual Sports
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;An anecdote that struck me was the story of the trips to the competitions. Although water skiing is an individual sport, Daniele described how the trips were moments of fun and community. I particularly remember the episode of the 2 athletes in wheelchairs stuck in the room and Daniele who had to resolve the situation.
He showed me that even in individual sports there is room for sharing and friendship, making the experience even richer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meeting Daniele Cassioli was one of the most significant experiences I have ever lived, and I will carry his teachings with me. His story taught me to see life from a different perspective and to believe that difficulties are not a limit, but an opportunity to grow and live fully.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I leave the live of the event here&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video-wrapper&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
            src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/7Yx9_MLF5vE&#34; 
            allowfullscreen 
            title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;
    &gt;
    &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Don&#39;t Brag</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/02_thought/humility/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/02_thought/humility/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/02_thought/humility/image.png" alt="Featured image of post Don&#39;t Brag" /&gt;&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-importance-of-humility-but-without-losing-self-confidence&#34;&gt;The importance of humility, but without losing self-confidence
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Humility is one of the most appreciated and sought-after qualities, both in personal and professional life. Being humble helps us grow, learn from others and recognize that we do not always have all the answers. It allows us to approach people with respect, creating authentic relationships based on mutual esteem. But it is important to remember that, like all virtues, humility must also be cultivated with balance.
&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/02_thought/humility/napkin-selection-4.png&#34;
	width=&#34;3888&#34;
	height=&#34;2238&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/02_thought/humility/napkin-selection-4_hu8802562197474333218.png 480w, http://localhost:1313/02_thought/humility/napkin-selection-4_hu17024578509287882581.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;173&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;416px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;when-humility-becomes-a-limit&#34;&gt;When humility becomes a limit
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, there is an insidious risk that hides behind excessive humility. While on the one hand it can be a sign of maturity and wisdom, on the other it can turn into a trap that undermines self-confidence. Being excessively humble can lead to underestimating one&amp;rsquo;s abilities, to belittling one&amp;rsquo;s successes or even to avoiding opportunities for fear of not being &amp;ldquo;enough&amp;rdquo; to face them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a world where comparing ourselves to others is the order of the day, it is easy to fall into the trap of thinking that humility means self-deprecation or extreme modesty. But being humble does not mean belittling yourself, but rather recognizing your limits without losing sight of your strengths. Humility must coexist with a healthy dose of self-esteem.
&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/02_thought/humility/napkin-selection-2.png&#34;
	width=&#34;4104&#34;
	height=&#34;3816&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/02_thought/humility/napkin-selection-2_hu3136251062340009860.png 480w, http://localhost:1313/02_thought/humility/napkin-selection-2_hu10690465949415309701.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;107&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;258px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cultivating-a-balance-humility-and-self-confidence&#34;&gt;Cultivating a balance: Humility and Self-Confidence
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The ideal balance consists of recognizing your own value without falling into arrogance. We can be aware of our skills, celebrating successes with gratitude but without turning them into vanity. We must learn to recognize what we have achieved without feeling superior to others, but also without belittling our path.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To achieve this balance, it is useful to ask yourself: &amp;ldquo;Am I rejecting this recognition because I am truly humble, or because I do not believe in myself enough?&amp;rdquo; Cultivating self-confidence does not mean becoming arrogant, but having the awareness of your own abilities to confidently face challenges and goals.
&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/02_thought/humility/napkin-selection-3.png&#34;
	width=&#34;4969&#34;
	height=&#34;3573&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/02_thought/humility/napkin-selection-3_hu9076800383919372593.png 480w, http://localhost:1313/02_thought/humility/napkin-selection-3_hu10908590416667283626.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;139&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;333px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-conclusion&#34;&gt;In Conclusion
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Humility and self-confidence are not conflicting qualities, but two sides of the same coin. Being humble keeps us grounded in reality, but having self-confidence pushes us to dream bigger and face challenges without fear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Humility does not consist in thinking less of yourself, but in thinking less of yourself.” – &lt;em&gt;C.S. Lewis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/02_thought/humility/napkin-selectiona.png&#34;
	width=&#34;3528&#34;
	height=&#34;1728&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/02_thought/humility/napkin-selectiona_hu2986713959833747791.png 480w, http://localhost:1313/02_thought/humility/napkin-selectiona_hu7098780543284844094.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;204&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;490px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>History importance</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/02_thought/history/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/02_thought/history/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/02_thought/history/history.png" alt="Featured image of post History importance" /&gt;&lt;h1 id=&#34;my-journey-from-hater-to-curious&#34;&gt;My Journey from Hater to Curious
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;I admit that history was my nemesis during my school years. When the professor entered the classroom and started talking about dates, battles and rulers, I felt lost. It all seemed so boring and distant from my reality. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t perceive the value of that knowledge: why on earth would I be interested in what had happened centuries ago?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the years, however, something changed. I began to realize my gaps, feeling ashamed of how little I knew about our past (not with others but with myself). I understood that ignoring history was not only an academic shortcoming, but a real limitation in understanding the world around me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;discovering-the-value-of-history&#34;&gt;Discovering the Value of History
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;What once seemed useless to me, today appears as a precious resource. Why? Because history is cyclical. Events of the past, in different forms, are still repeated today. If we look carefully, we can find surprising analogies between what happened in the past centuries and what is happening in the world today. Economic crises, social tensions, international conflicts: it seems that humanity is condemned to continually relive the same mistakes (and this makes me think a lot).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understanding history has given me an additional tool to interpret the present. The more I study past events, the more I realize that it is not just a matter of memorizing dates and names, but of recognizing patterns, dynamics and cycles that recur.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;learning-from-the-mistakes-of-others&#34;&gt;Learning from the mistakes of others
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the most valuable lessons I have learned is that history is not just a book of past facts, but a practical guide for the present and above all for the future. Observing how leaders of the past have moved, what decisions they have made (and what mistakes they have made), allows me to draw lessons that I can also apply in my life. I am not just talking about political or economic decisions, but also about how to deal with difficult or unexpected situations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a way, knowing history is like having a map of the territory: it helps you orient yourself, avoid obstacles and not repeat the same mistakes made by those who came before us. Learning from the mistakes of others is a way to save time and pain, taking advantage of the wisdom accumulated over the centuries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-commitment-to-improving&#34;&gt;My commitment to improving
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today, I try to make up for lost time, also because nowadays ignorance is a choice given that you can watch documentaries for free, listen to podcasts that delve into historical events and many other contents are available to everyone. I can&amp;rsquo;t change my school past, but I can certainly enrich my present.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not an easy process: there are still times when I feel overwhelmed by all the information I don&amp;rsquo;t know. But I don&amp;rsquo;t let myself get discouraged. Every day that passes, I discover something new that helps me better understand the world I live in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Those who don&amp;rsquo;t know history are condemned to repeat it.” – &lt;em&gt;George Santayana&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And with this quote, I want to remind myself (and whoever reads) that the past is not just a lesson for historians, but an opportunity for each of us to grow and improve.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>repetition is the mother of all skills</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/02_thought/repetition/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/02_thought/repetition/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/02_thought/repetition/i.png" alt="Featured image of post repetition is the mother of all skills" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;There’s a timeless truth in the saying, &lt;em&gt;“Repetition is the mother of all skills.”&lt;/em&gt; It’s something I’ve come to embrace fully since I integrated a method that has completely transformed the way I learn and internalize concepts: &lt;strong&gt;the immersion method&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-the-immersion-method&#34;&gt;What is the Immersion Method?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The immersion method is exactly what it sounds like—a full, deep dive into the subject or skill you want to master. Instead of just skimming the surface or approaching learning sporadically, immersion means surrounding yourself with the material, over and over again, until it becomes second nature. It’s not just about repetition but also about consistency and engagement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s how I applied it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Daily Exposure&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I made sure to interact with the concepts every single day. Whether it was listening to a podcast, reading a book, taking notes, or even talking about it with others, I created a constant feedback loop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Active Repetition&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Instead of passively consuming material, I actively revisited it. For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I reread the same books multiple times. Each read revealed something I missed the first time or offered new insights as my understanding deepened.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I rewrote my notes. This process helped reinforce the key points in my mind.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Practical Application&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Immersion wasn’t just theoretical. I put what I learned into practice in real-world scenarios, which solidified the knowledge in my subconscious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;from-subconscious-absorption-to-visible-results&#34;&gt;From Subconscious Absorption to Visible Results
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The most incredible change I experienced was seeing how concepts that once felt elusive started to flow naturally. It’s as if they had seeped into my subconscious. I no longer had to think so hard to recall them; they were just &lt;em&gt;there&lt;/em&gt;, ready for use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, while studying personal development topics, I found that principles I’d been exposed to for weeks suddenly became part of my decision-making process. I didn’t have to remind myself to “stay present” or “focus on the process” anymore—it just happened. This transformation wasn’t magic; it was immersion at work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-repetition-is-crucial&#34;&gt;Why Repetition is Crucial
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Repetition isn’t boring; it’s foundational. Every time you revisit a concept:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You &lt;strong&gt;strengthen the neural pathways&lt;/strong&gt; in your brain, making recall faster and easier.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You see new perspectives that weren’t apparent the first time. A single read-through of a book or course can’t uncover all its wisdom.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s what I’ve learned about the power of repetition:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Books are meant to be reread.&lt;/strong&gt; Some of my favorite books have been revisited three or four times, and each time I gain new insights or reinforce old ones.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learning never stops.&lt;/strong&gt; What seems redundant often turns out to be the foundation for mastery.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-impact-of-immersion-on-me&#34;&gt;The Impact of Immersion on Me
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The immersion method has had a profound effect on my growth, both personally and professionally. Not only have I seen results in terms of knowledge retention, but also in how I think and act. Concepts that I struggled to grasp now feel second nature, and my confidence has skyrocketed because I trust in the process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;final-thoughts-repetition-as-a-way-of-life&#34;&gt;Final Thoughts: Repetition as a Way of Life
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a world obsessed with novelty, we often undervalue repetition. But true mastery isn’t about skimming through countless books or ideas; it’s about deeply understanding and integrating a few. Immersion and repetition are how you turn knowledge into action and action into habits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, let me leave you with this:&lt;br&gt;
Revisit that book you love. Redo that course you enjoyed. Practice that skill over and over. You might be surprised by how much growth lies in going &lt;em&gt;deeper&lt;/em&gt;, not wider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are your thoughts on repetition and immersion? Have you tried applying these principles to your learning or personal growth? Share your experiences below!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Atomic Habits | James Clear</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/06_books/atomic-habits/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:31:32 +0100</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/06_books/atomic-habits/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/06_books/atomic-habits/image.png" alt="Featured image of post Atomic Habits | James Clear" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Atomic Habits&amp;rdquo; by James Clear is an enlightening book that addresses the importance of habits in our daily lives. In a clear and accessible style, the author guides us through the cycle of habits, explaining how they influence our behavior and how we can use them to improve our lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary-of-the-book&#34;&gt;Summary of the Book
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The heart of &amp;ldquo;Atomic Habits&amp;rdquo; is the explanation of how small, seemingly insignificant habits can accumulate over time to produce big results. The book provides a practical structure for building good habits and breaking bad ones, based on four fundamental laws: &lt;strong&gt;Cue, Craving, Response and Reward&lt;/strong&gt;. These elements make up the cycle of habits, a psychological process that determines our behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-cycle-of-habits-the-key-point-of-the-book&#34;&gt;The Cycle of Habits: The Key Point of the Book
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;James Clear teaches us that every habit follows a cycle composed of four main phases:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cue&lt;/strong&gt;: A stimulus that starts the habit. It can be something we see, hear or feel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Desire&lt;/strong&gt;: The motivation or impulse to do something. This is where the intention to act is born.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Response&lt;/strong&gt;: The action or behavior itself, which can be good or bad.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reward&lt;/strong&gt;: The positive (or negative) result that strengthens the likelihood of repeating that habit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-usefulness-of-habits&#34;&gt;The Usefulness of Habits
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Habits can be a very powerful tool if we know how to exploit them. For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create positive habits&lt;/strong&gt;: Getting used to reading every day even for just a few minutes can transform our cultural and mental life.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Make changes sustainable&lt;/strong&gt;: Focusing on small but constant improvements (1% every day, as Clear suggests) can lead us to great progress in the long term.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;when-habits-become-dangerous&#34;&gt;When Habits Become Dangerous
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Habits are not always positive. If left unchecked, they can turn into harmful mechanisms, such as giving in to laziness or adopting self-destructive behaviors. The important thing, according to Clear, is to recognize these patterns and change them using the habit cycle as a tool for awareness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Atomic Habits&amp;rdquo; is not just a book about habits, but a real guide to personal growth. Learning to recognize and control the habit cycle allows us to build the life we ​​want, one small step at a time. It is a reading that I recommend to anyone who wants to improve themselves, both personally and professionally.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Cars</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/05_passions/car/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:31:32 +0100</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/05_passions/car/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/05_passions/car/IMG_8411.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Cars" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fueled by passion and the unforgettable roar of petrol engines, this blog is a tribute to the timeless allure of cars. From a young age, I was mesmerized by the hum of engines, the thrill of watching cars fly by on the road, and the unmistakable connection I felt with each machine. Here, I dive into everything that makes cars more than just vehicles—from the technical finesse of engineering to the pure adrenaline sparked by the sound of a finely-tuned engine. Join me as I explore the art, performance, and culture of cars, where every drive feels like a shared heartbeat between driver and machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;youtube-video-about&#34;&gt;YouTube Video About
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;video-wrapper&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
            src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/kb6g_65PPoY&#34; 
            allowfullscreen 
            title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;
    &gt;
    &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Guadagna con la mente | Andrea Maurizio Gilardoni</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/06_books/mente-guadagna/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:31:32 +0100</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/06_books/mente-guadagna/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/06_books/mente-guadagna/image.png" alt="Featured image of post Guadagna con la mente | Andrea Maurizio Gilardoni" /&gt;&lt;h1 id=&#34;comming-soon-still-reading&#34;&gt;COMMING SOON, Still Reading
&lt;/h1&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>guida ai bias cognitivi, Capire le Trappole della Mente | Raffaele Gaito</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/06_books/bias-cognitivi/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:31:32 +0100</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/06_books/bias-cognitivi/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/06_books/bias-cognitivi/image.png" alt="Featured image of post guida ai bias cognitivi, Capire le Trappole della Mente | Raffaele Gaito" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Cognitive Bias Guide&lt;/em&gt; is a book that helps us discover and understand the mechanisms that influence our thinking and decisions. Cognitive biases are systematic errors that we all make in reasoning, often without realizing it. This book offers practical examples and ideas to recognize and address these mental traps, allowing us to improve our decision-making process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;book-summary&#34;&gt;Book Summary
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Cognitive Bias Guide&lt;/em&gt; explores how our mind simplifies reality to save energy, but at the cost of introducing distortions in reasoning. It explains why cognitive biases develop and how they affect different aspects of our lives, from everyday choices to important decisions. Among the biases covered, we find:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Confirmation bias&lt;/strong&gt;: The tendency to seek information that confirms our beliefs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Dunning-Kruger effect&lt;/strong&gt;: The overestimation of one&amp;rsquo;s own skills by those with little experience in a field.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Loss Aversion&lt;/strong&gt;: The tendency to fear losses more than we value gains.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;understanding-cognitive-biases-the-key-point-of-the-book&#34;&gt;Understanding Cognitive Biases: The Key Point of the Book
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The book shows us how cognitive biases are the result of heuristics, or mental shortcuts that the brain uses to deal with the complexity of the world. These shortcuts, while on the one hand helping us save time, on the other hand can lead us to incorrect conclusions or suboptimal choices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;examples-of-cognitive-biases&#34;&gt;Examples of Cognitive Biases
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Confirmation Bias&lt;/strong&gt;: Imagine wanting to buy a new smartphone and only reading reviews that speak positively of it, ignoring the negative ones.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Availability Heuristic&lt;/strong&gt;: Estimating the probability of an event based on easily remembered examples, such as thinking that plane crashes are more frequent than they actually are just because we hear about them on the news.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Framing Effect&lt;/strong&gt;: Changing your opinion on a proposal based on how it is presented (for example, preferring a product &amp;ldquo;90% fat free&amp;rdquo; to one &amp;ldquo;with 10% fat&amp;rdquo;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-is-it-important-to-recognize-them&#34;&gt;Why is it Important to Recognize Them?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Being aware of cognitive biases allows us to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Avoid recurring errors&lt;/strong&gt;: For example, we can reduce the impact of confirmation bias by actively seeking opposing points of view.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Improve decisions&lt;/strong&gt;: In both our personal and professional lives, recognizing our biases makes us more objective.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Promote critical thinking&lt;/strong&gt;: Becoming more aware of our cognitive limitations pushes us to think more deeply.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Guide to Cognitive Biases&lt;/em&gt; is an essential book for anyone who wants to improve their mental awareness and make more informed decisions. It is an inspiring read, full of examples that invites us to examine the way we think and discover how to avoid the most common mental traps.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>ignorance nowadays is a choice</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/02_thought/ignorance-today/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:31:32 +0100</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/02_thought/ignorance-today/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/02_thought/ignorance-today/al.png" alt="Featured image of post ignorance nowadays is a choice" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the past, access to knowledge was a privilege. Books were scarce, universities were reserved for the elite, and expertise often required access to specialized mentors or tools. But today, the story is completely different. We live in an era where the barriers to learning have all but disappeared, thanks to the transformative power of technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-gift-of-unlimited-access&#34;&gt;The Gift of Unlimited Access
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The internet, smartphones, and countless platforms like YouTube, Coursera, Udemy, and even Wikipedia have democratized information. Want to master photography? There&amp;rsquo;s a free tutorial for that. Fascinated by astrophysics? Enroll in an online course taught by a renowned professor. Curious about coding? Interactive coding platforms and forums can turn you into a developer from the comfort of your home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This unprecedented access means that anyone with a genuine passion and determination can become an expert in virtually any field. The tools are there, waiting to be used. Ignorance, in many ways, is no longer an excuse. It has become a choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-challenge-information-overload&#34;&gt;The Challenge: Information Overload
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, with great access comes great responsibility. The same internet that empowers us is also flooded with misinformation, half-truths, and outright falsehoods. Separating valuable, accurate knowledge from noise has become a skill in itself. Critical thinking and a skeptical eye are essential for navigating this sea of information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are a few tips to ensure you&amp;rsquo;re learning from reliable sources:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Check the credentials&lt;/strong&gt; of the author or creator. Are they an expert in the field?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cross-reference information&lt;/strong&gt; across multiple reputable sources.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Look for peer-reviewed or fact-checked content.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Beware of biases&lt;/strong&gt;, especially in sensational or overly opinionated materials.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-future-of-self-education&#34;&gt;The Future of Self-Education
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;As technology continues to evolve, so will the tools for self-education. Artificial intelligence, virtual reality, and augmented reality are already shaping the way we learn, making it more interactive and immersive. But one thing remains constant: the drive to learn must come from within.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By embracing the resources at our fingertips and being mindful of the content we consume, we can unlock boundless potential. The only question left is: what will you choose to learn today?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;The beautiful thing about learning is that no one can take it away from you.&amp;rdquo; – B.B. King&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>il grifone | Nicola Gratteri</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/06_books/gratteri/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:31:32 +0100</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/06_books/gratteri/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/06_books/gratteri/image.png" alt="Featured image of post il grifone | Nicola Gratteri" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Il Grifone&lt;/em&gt;, written by Nicola Gratteri, is a work that goes beyond the simple narration of the fight against organized crime. This book represents a true manifesto of dedication to justice, embodied by the author himself. Gratteri, magistrate and symbol of the fight against the &amp;rsquo;ndrangheta, dedicates every moment of his life to this mission, sacrificing his personal time and the comforts that his position could guarantee him (a characteristic that fascinates me a lot).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;book-summary&#34;&gt;Book Summary
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Il Grifone&lt;/em&gt; tells stories of corruption, organized crime and the constant challenge to defend the rule of law. Gratteri does not limit himself to describing the mechanisms of the &amp;rsquo;ndrangheta: he also illustrates the strategies to fight it, highlighting the importance of a strong, cohesive and determined judiciary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The title of the book, symbolic and evocative, refers to a mythological creature that represents vigilance and strength: qualities that well describe Gratteri himself in his daily commitment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;nicola-gratteri-a-fascinating-comparison-with-paolo-borsellino&#34;&gt;Nicola Gratteri: A Fascinating Comparison with Paolo Borsellino
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reading &lt;em&gt;Il Grifone&lt;/em&gt; and listening to interviews with Nicola Gratteri, it is impossible not to notice a parallel with figures such as Paolo Borsellino. Like Borsellino, Gratteri has chosen to dedicate every aspect of his life to working for justice, sacrificing his personal life and giving up many privileges to remain faithful to his mission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;total-dedication&#34;&gt;Total Dedication
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nicola Gratteri lives under escort, constantly aware of the risks that his role entails. However, he does not seek recognition or indulgence: his commitment is driven by a deep moral conviction and the desire to leave a better world for future generations. This dedication leads him to give up a private life and those moments of normality that many of us take for granted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;an-example-of-sacrifice-and-courage&#34;&gt;An Example of Sacrifice and Courage
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Like Paolo Borsellino, Gratteri also demonstrates that justice is a value that requires absolute commitment. Both represent figures who put the collective good first, even at the cost of putting aside their own well-being and personal safety. This aspect makes their example not only admirable, but also deeply inspiring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-il-grifone-is-important&#34;&gt;Why &lt;em&gt;Il Grifone&lt;/em&gt; is Important
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This book is not only a work of denunciation, but also a reflection on how dedication and sacrifice are necessary to face seemingly insurmountable challenges. Gratteri not only describes the reality of organized crime, but invites us to reflect on the collective responsibility in building a more just society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nicola Gratteri, through &lt;em&gt;Il Grifone&lt;/em&gt;, does not only give us an account of the fight against the &amp;rsquo;ndrangheta, but a life lesson. His dedication recalls that of Paolo Borsellino, becoming an example of sacrifice, courage and integrity. This book is essential reading for anyone who wants to understand the price and value of justice.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>il vento contro | Daniele Cassioli</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/06_books/cassioli-cuore-a-vedere/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:31:32 +0100</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/06_books/cassioli-cuore-a-vedere/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/06_books/cassioli-cuore-a-vedere/image.png" alt="Featured image of post il vento contro | Daniele Cassioli" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction-the-power-to-transform-adversity-into-opportunity&#34;&gt;Introduction, The Power to Transform Adversity into Opportunity
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Il Vento Contro&lt;/em&gt; by Daniele Cassioli is a book about resilience, courage and the ability to see life&amp;rsquo;s challenges as opportunities to grow. Cassioli, a Paralympic athlete who has been blind since birth, is an extraordinary example of how it is possible to overcome the limits imposed by circumstances and live a full and meaningful life. The book is a journey through personal experiences, reflections and lessons that inspire anyone who reads it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;book-summary&#34;&gt;Book Summary
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In &lt;em&gt;Il Vento Contro&lt;/em&gt;, Daniele Cassioli talks about his life and his journey as a water skier, but above all as a man who has been able to transform blindness into a strength. Among the pages we find:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Daily challenges&lt;/strong&gt;: How to face a world designed for those who can see, without ever losing the desire to improve.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Passion for sport&lt;/strong&gt;: Cassioli shows that sport is not just competition, but also a powerful tool for inclusion and personal growth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Universal Lessons&lt;/strong&gt;: Through anecdotes and reflections, Daniele teaches us that every obstacle, even the most difficult, can become a push to move forward.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The title, &lt;em&gt;The Wind Against&lt;/em&gt;, perfectly represents the idea that difficulties should not stop us, but can be used to gain momentum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-wind-against-a-message-of-resilience&#34;&gt;The Wind Against: A Message of Resilience
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;A central theme of the book is the ability to see the headwind not as an enemy, but as an opportunity to grow and become stronger. Cassioli invites us to reflect on how we react to adversity and shows us that the real limit often lies in our mind, not in external circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-example-of-daniele-cassioli&#34;&gt;The Example of Daniele Cassioli
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;What makes &lt;em&gt;The Wind Against&lt;/em&gt; so powerful is the authenticity of Daniele&amp;rsquo;s story. His life is a concrete example of resilience and determination:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overcoming one&amp;rsquo;s limits&lt;/strong&gt;: Despite being blind, Cassioli has become an award-winning athlete, demonstrating that success is a matter of mindset.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finding Strength in Difficulty&lt;/strong&gt;: Daniele explains how his challenges helped him develop extraordinary skills, such as listening and greater awareness of the world.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inspiring Others&lt;/strong&gt;: Through his story, Daniele conveys a message of hope to anyone who finds themselves facing a &amp;ldquo;headwind&amp;rdquo; in their life.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-opinion&#34;&gt;My Opinion
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I found &lt;em&gt;Il Vento Contro&lt;/em&gt; deeply inspiring, especially for Cassioli&amp;rsquo;s ability to transform every adversity into an opportunity for growth. However, I must admit that some reflections seemed familiar to me, having read other personal growth books. Despite this, the strength of the book lies in the authenticity of Daniele&amp;rsquo;s voice and in his ability to make his experiences universal, which I was able to experience during the inauguration of the 2024/2025 academic year in which Daniele participated and gave a speech lasting 1:30h.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-read-il-vento-contro&#34;&gt;Why Read &lt;em&gt;Il Vento Contro&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This book is an essential read for those seeking inspiration to face their challenges. Daniele Cassioli&amp;rsquo;s story reminds us that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resilience is a choice&lt;/strong&gt;: We can choose how to react to difficulties.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Every limit can become a strength&lt;/strong&gt;: It all depends on how we face it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Life is an opportunity, despite everything&lt;/strong&gt;: Even when it seems impossible, we can find a way to move forward.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Il Vento Contro&lt;/em&gt; by Daniele Cassioli is a book that speaks to the heart and mind. It is a life testimony that invites us to look beyond appearances and find the strength within ourselves to face any difficulty. A work that I recommend to anyone who wants to discover the true meaning of resilience.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>insegna al cuore a vedere | Daniele Cassioli</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/06_books/cassioli-ventro-contro/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:31:32 +0100</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/06_books/cassioli-ventro-contro/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/06_books/cassioli-ventro-contro/image.png" alt="Featured image of post insegna al cuore a vedere | Daniele Cassioli" /&gt;&lt;h1 id=&#34;comming-soon-still-reading&#34;&gt;COMMING SOON, Still Reading
&lt;/h1&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Life Appreciation</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/02_thought/gratitude/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:31:32 +0100</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/02_thought/gratitude/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/02_thought/gratitude/grateful.jpeg" alt="Featured image of post Life Appreciation" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;We often live in a rush, projected towards new goals and expectations. In this vortex, we can take for granted what we have: our health, our family, the people who love us, or even the simple warmth of the sun on our skin. Yet, when we learn to stop and really “see” these things, we discover a source of serenity and strength that can change our way of living.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-beauty-of-everyday-life&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Beauty of Everyday Life&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Being grateful does not only mean recognizing great achievements or resounding successes, but also stopping to observe what surrounds us. It may seem trivial, but appreciating a morning coffee, a sincere smile, or the hug of a dear friend has immense value. These moments remind us that happiness does not lie in great events, but in the sum of many small moments lived with awareness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The simplest things, often the quietest, are those that resonate most within us.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;gratitude-for-health-and-relationships&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gratitude for Health and Relationships&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Health is one of the most precious gifts we possess and that we usually tend to notice only when it is lacking. Practicing gratitude for our body and its ability to allow us to live and experience is a first step towards a deeper appreciation of ourselves and life. Relationships, whether they are family or friends, give us the opportunity to feel understood, supported and loved. And this too is never a given.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-power-of-nature-sunsets-the-sun-and-the-cycle-of-the-seasons&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Power of Nature: Sunsets, the Sun and the Cycle of the Seasons&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The natural world is full of beauty and wonder, and just taking a few minutes to observe it can instantly make you feel more serene and grounded. Watching a sunset, feeling the wind on your skin, or perceiving the warmth of the sun helps us reconnect to the present and appreciate the simplicity of life. These moments do not require money or status; they are there, every day, for anyone who wants to stop and experience them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-journey-of-gratitude-a-growth-path&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Journey of Gratitude: A Growth Path&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I came to these thoughts thanks to some personal growth courses that I took. In particular, one of the courses that had a significant impact on me was &lt;em&gt;Optimism and Resilience&lt;/em&gt; by Nicoletta Stella, which I attended during my time at the Collegio di Merito Don Mazza in Verona. This course helped me develop a more open and resilient mindset, making me understand how important it is to appreciate every aspect of life, even in difficult moments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;gratitude-practices-in-daily-life&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gratitude Practices in Daily Life&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;For anyone who wants to start practicing gratitude, here are some practical tips:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Write a gratitude journal&lt;/strong&gt;: Every day, write down three things you are grateful for. They can be simple, like the food you ate or a pleasant conversation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stop and reflect&lt;/strong&gt;: Every time you feel a positive emotion, try to stop and live it fully, without thinking about what comes after.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Expressing Gratitude to Others&lt;/strong&gt;: Saying “thank you” to someone or letting them know how much they mean to you can improve not only your mood, but also the bond between you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Life as a Gift&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In conclusion living appreciating what you have doesn’t mean not trying to improve yourself or reach new goals. It means remembering that every moment has a value and that we are part of a unique and unrepeatable experience. Being grateful for everyday things – from the bonds with those we love to the simple pleasures of nature – helps us cultivate a fuller and more satisfying life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Appreciating life means finding beauty even in simple moments, welcoming every moment as a gift, and recognizing that true happiness comes from gratitude for what we already have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video-wrapper&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
            src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/g-3IHnZm4G8&#34; 
            allowfullscreen 
            title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;
    &gt;
    &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Motorbikes</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/05_passions/motorbike/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:31:32 +0100</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/05_passions/motorbike/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/05_passions/motorbike/fantic.jpeg" alt="Featured image of post Motorbikes" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/05_passions/motorbike/fantic.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1080&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/05_passions/motorbike/fantic_hu10077127944113824026.jpg 480w, http://localhost:1313/05_passions/motorbike/fantic_hu10277045893864623639.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;My Fantic 50 Motard&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;
Born from a lifelong craving for the thrill of two wheels, this blog captures the essence of my journey into the world of motorbikes. Ever since I was young, I dreamt of owning my own bike, and when I finally got my Fantic 50 2-stroke, it was everything I’d imagined—and more. From personalizing it to make it uniquely mine, to mastering the art of riding on one wheel, every ride brought a rush of freedom and exhilaration. Here, I’ll share stories, tips, and insights into the motorbike lifestyle, celebrating the pure adrenaline, skill, and connection that only bikers understand. Whether you’re a seasoned rider or just curious, join me on the ride!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Mountain bike</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/05_passions/bike/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:31:32 +0100</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/05_passions/bike/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/05_passions/bike/bike.JPG" alt="Featured image of post Mountain bike" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/05_passions/bike/mountainbike.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1080&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/05_passions/bike/mountainbike_hu4849987664021280301.jpg 480w, http://localhost:1313/05_passions/bike/mountainbike_hu8333773938812547352.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Me exploring the beauty of Rabbi Valley&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;
This blog is all about the adrenaline, freedom, and connection with nature that mountain biking has brought into my life. Ever since my first ride, I was hooked—there’s nothing like the thrill of hitting rugged trails, mastering new terrain, and feeling the rush of carving through mountainsides.
From discovering the best gear and customizing my setup to push my limits, to the pure satisfaction of conquering new trails, mountain biking has become more than a sport—it’s a passion. Here, I’ll share tips, personal stories, trail reviews, and everything that makes mountain biking an adventure worth chasing. Whether you’re a seasoned rider or a curious beginner, join me in exploring the world on two wheels!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Mountain Hiking</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/05_passions/hiking/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:31:32 +0100</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/05_passions/hiking/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/05_passions/hiking/rabbi.JPG" alt="Featured image of post Mountain Hiking" /&gt;&lt;h1 id=&#34;-comming-soon&#34;&gt;# comming soon&amp;hellip;
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/05_passions/hiking/sfondo.JPG&#34;
	width=&#34;4032&#34;
	height=&#34;3024&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/05_passions/hiking/sfondo_hu6737264303993248711.JPG 480w, http://localhost:1313/05_passions/hiking/sfondo_hu15090278562224046264.JPG 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;133&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;320px&#34;
	
&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/05_passions/hiking/alba.JPG&#34;
	width=&#34;4032&#34;
	height=&#34;3024&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/05_passions/hiking/alba_hu13369600799418941076.JPG 480w, http://localhost:1313/05_passions/hiking/alba_hu10960277893557734281.JPG 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;133&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;320px&#34;
	
&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/05_passions/hiking/rabb.JPG&#34;
	width=&#34;4032&#34;
	height=&#34;3024&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/05_passions/hiking/rabb_hu569680403830225041.JPG 480w, http://localhost:1313/05_passions/hiking/rabb_hu263668569943984736.JPG 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;133&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;320px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Pensieri lenti pensieri veloci</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/06_books/pensieri-lenti-pensieri-veloci/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:31:32 +0100</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/06_books/pensieri-lenti-pensieri-veloci/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/06_books/pensieri-lenti-pensieri-veloci/image.png" alt="Featured image of post Pensieri lenti pensieri veloci" /&gt;&lt;h1 id=&#34;comming-soon-still-reading&#34;&gt;COMMING SOON, Still Reading
&lt;/h1&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Personal Growth</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/05_passions/persona-growth/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:31:32 +0100</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/05_passions/persona-growth/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/05_passions/persona-growth/grow.jpeg" alt="Featured image of post Personal Growth" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/05_passions/persona-growth/personalgrowth.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1080&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/05_passions/persona-growth/personalgrowth_hu15341732370339065581.jpg 480w, http://localhost:1313/05_passions/persona-growth/personalgrowth_hu11143947620885413600.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;as&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;
Embark on a journey of &lt;strong&gt;personal growth&lt;/strong&gt; and self-discovery! This blog is all about transforming life, one article, one book, and one action at a time. Starting with a simple curiosity, I dove into the world of personal development, reading about habits, resilience, mindfulness, and purpose. Each insight led to real changes in how I see myself, set goals, and make decisions. Here, I’ll share lessons from books and articles that have had the biggest impact on my life, along with actionable tips and reflections on the changes I’ve experienced. Join me in exploring the power of intentional self-improvement and see how small shifts can lead to profound personal transformation&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Rich and Poor Dad | Robert Kiyosaki</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/06_books/grow-rich/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:31:32 +0100</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/06_books/grow-rich/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/06_books/grow-rich/image.png" alt="Featured image of post Rich and Poor Dad | Robert Kiyosaki" /&gt;&lt;h1 id=&#34;rich-dad-poor-dad-personal-finance-for-everyone&#34;&gt;Rich Dad Poor Dad: Personal Finance for Everyone?
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rich Dad Poor Dad&lt;/em&gt; by Robert Kiyosaki is one of the most popular books in the world of personal finance. First published in 1997, it chronicles the lessons the author learned from two father figures: “Rich Dad” (the father of a friend who is a successful entrepreneur) and “Poor Dad” (Kiyosaki’s biological father who is educated but stuck in an employee mentality). The book aims to teach money management and investing principles, emphasizing the importance of changing one’s approach to wealth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;book-summary&#34;&gt;Book Summary
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The central message of &lt;em&gt;Rich Dad Poor Dad&lt;/em&gt; revolves around a series of contrasts between two approaches to financial life:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Employee Mentality vs. entrepreneurial mindset&lt;/strong&gt;: While “Poor Dad” promotes traditional education and a stable job, “Rich Dad” emphasizes the importance of creating passive income streams through investments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Actives vs. Passives&lt;/strong&gt;: According to Kiyosaki, the goal should be to accumulate assets (assets that generate income) and reduce liabilities (expenses that take money away).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learn to make money work for you&lt;/strong&gt;: A key lesson is that money should be seen as a tool to be put to work, rather than simply earning a paycheck.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book is written in a simple and accessible way, designed for a broad audience and those new to the world of personal finance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-take-interesting-but-overrated&#34;&gt;My Take: Interesting, but Overrated
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Despite its popularity, I have to admit that I found the book to be a bit overrated. For someone like me who grew up in a family with an entrepreneur father, many of the concepts Kiyosaki explains are trivial or already known. Since I was a child, I have heard teachings such as “invest in assets” or “create sources of passive income”. These are things that I have always breathed and that have been transmitted to me as part of the entrepreneurial mentality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-it-can-be-useful-for-others&#34;&gt;Why It Can Be Useful for Others
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Despite this, I recognize the value of &lt;em&gt;Rich Dad Poor Dad&lt;/em&gt; for those starting from scratch. The book offers a clear and accessible perspective on money management, breaking some taboos and challenging the idea that financial success depends only on the traditional school path. For those who have never had access to these concepts, the book can represent a turning point and an introduction to the world of finance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;strengths&#34;&gt;Strengths
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Simplicity&lt;/strong&gt;: Kiyosaki uses concrete examples and direct language.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Motivation&lt;/strong&gt;: The book pushes you to reflect on your approach to money and the possibilities of changing your life.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Focus on financial education&lt;/strong&gt;: An aspect often overlooked in traditional education.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;limitations&#34;&gt;Limitations
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Little depth&lt;/strong&gt;: For those who are already familiar with finance or grew up in an entrepreneurial context, the book may seem superficial.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Repetitiveness&lt;/strong&gt;: Many concepts are reiterated several times, without adding new details, which is a great thing if it is the first time you come into contact with certain information ( IMPORTANCE OF REPETITION found in Thought -&amp;gt; Repetition is the mother of all skills ), but if you already have a smattering of knowledge it becomes boring.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Examples not always practical&lt;/strong&gt;: Some advice is difficult to apply for those who do not have starting resources.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rich Dad Poor Dad&lt;/em&gt; is certainly an interesting book for those who want to approach the topics of personal finance in a simple and immediate way. However, for those who already have a solid foundation or come from an entrepreneurial context, it could be less stimulating and, in some cases, obvious. However, it remains a work that has the merit of having made the dialogue on money management accessible to a very wide audience.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Ski</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/05_passions/ski/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:31:32 +0100</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/05_passions/ski/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/05_passions/ski/logo.JPG" alt="Featured image of post Ski" /&gt;&lt;h1 id=&#34;comming-soon&#34;&gt;comming soon&amp;hellip;
&lt;/h1&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The 20th century Trap</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/02_thought/trap/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:31:32 +0100</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/02_thought/trap/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/02_thought/trap/traps.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The 20th century Trap" /&gt;&lt;h1 id=&#34;detached-from-stimuli&#34;&gt;Detached from stimuli
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;We live in an age of constant stimulation, a constant flow of notifications, updates and digital content that keep us constantly &amp;ldquo;connected&amp;rdquo; but, at the same time, drastically reduce our ability to concentrate. Every day, we are bombarded with visual and auditory stimuli through social media, messaging apps, entertainment platforms, which now guide our lives both online and offline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-loss-of-attention-span&#34;&gt;The Loss of Attention Span
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This situation scares me. I have noticed, especially during the pandemic, how much social media has taken on the role of &amp;ldquo;directors&amp;rdquo; of our lives. People talk about news, trends, and aspects of other people&amp;rsquo;s lives that they have learned on social media, as if these have replaced real experiences. Our attention span has reduced to almost absurd levels: we are incapable of standing in line or waiting without taking out our phones in search of new stimuli. This constant search for instant gratification through digital devices deprives us of the ability to fully live in the moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;an-incredibly-addicted-generation&#34;&gt;An Incredibly Addicted Generation
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is a big difference compared to when I was a child. I remember with nostalgia the time spent playing outside, running in the parks and socializing with friends. Now I see parents who have to force their children to go out because, as soon as they can, young people prefer to stay sunk on the couch, immersed in devices. This cultural change is fueled by social media, which offers continuous doses of dopamine pleasure, generating an addiction similar to that of chemical substances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;first-step-awareness&#34;&gt;First Step: Awareness
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The first step to free ourselves from this trap is to gain awareness. It is essential to understand how much social media and digital devices can suck us into their network, distancing us from real life and its most natural and authentic stimuli. If not managed with awareness, these tools can make us slaves to a virtual reality, making us lose connection with ourselves and with others in real life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-importance-of-being-bored&#34;&gt;The Importance of Being Bored
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Being bored has become almost a taboo in modern society, but it is a practice that brings incredible benefits. Being bored is an opportunity to reflect, to let your mind wander and to reconnect with your creativity. It is a state that can bring out deep thoughts and new ideas, a precious space in which the mind frees itself from incessant stimuli and learns to regenerate itself. Learning to enjoy the absence of stimuli is essential to regaining our attention and living a more balanced life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, the next time you feel the temptation to grab your phone during a break, try to resist. Let your mind free itself from the need for constant stimuli, embrace boredom and allow yourself to return to a more natural rhythm. This is the only way we can escape the &amp;ldquo;Social Trap&amp;rdquo; and regain our mental freedom.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>think and grow rich | Napoleon Hill</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/06_books/think/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:31:32 +0100</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/06_books/think/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/06_books/think/image.png" alt="Featured image of post think and grow rich | Napoleon Hill" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction-to-napoleon-hills-philosophy-of-success&#34;&gt;Introduction to Napoleon Hill&amp;rsquo;s Philosophy of Success
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Think and Grow Rich&lt;/em&gt; by Napoleon Hill is an evergreen in personal development and success. First published in 1937, it is a practical guide that teaches how positive thinking, determination and a clear vision of goals can transform dreams into reality. Hill has studied the lives of great successful men, such as Andrew Carnegie, Henry Ford and Thomas Edison, for over 25 years and has distilled their secrets into this timeless masterpiece.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;book-summary&#34;&gt;Book Summary
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The book is based on 13 fundamental principles that, according to Hill, are essential to achieving success. Among them:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Burn desire&lt;/strong&gt;: It all starts with an intense and well-defined desire.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Faith&lt;/strong&gt;: Firmly believing in your goals.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Autosuggestion&lt;/strong&gt;: Using positive affirmations to influence the subconscious.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Specialized knowledge&lt;/strong&gt;: Learning specific skills useful for your goals.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Perseverance&lt;/strong&gt;: Never give up, even in the face of difficulties.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hill emphasizes that success is not only material, but also involves personal growth, happiness and inner satisfaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-power-of-positive-thinking-and-vision&#34;&gt;The Power of Positive Thinking and Vision
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the central concepts of the book is the power of thought. Napoleon Hill explains that every great result starts with a clear idea and the belief that we can achieve it. Our mind is a very powerful tool, and by focusing on what we want, we attract the opportunities and resources necessary to achieve it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-importance-of-clear-goals&#34;&gt;The Importance of Clear Goals
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A key point of the book is that success does not come by chance: it is the result of defined goals and a well-structured plan. Hill recommends writing down your goals and rereading them every day, to keep your motivation and focus alive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sacrifice-and-perseverance-the-recipe-for-success&#34;&gt;Sacrifice and Perseverance: The Recipe for Success
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hill emphasizes that success requires sacrifice, dedication and strong perseverance. There will be obstacles along the way, but what distinguishes those who succeed from those who fail is the ability to stay the course despite the difficulties. This approach is very similar to the concept of “resilience”, which is still essential today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-think-and-grow-rich-is-still-current&#34;&gt;Why &lt;em&gt;Think and Grow Rich&lt;/em&gt; is Still Current
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Despite having been written almost a century ago, the message of the book remains extremely relevant. Hill&amp;rsquo;s principles are universal and applicable in every aspect of life: from work to family, from personal relationships to the most ambitious dreams. The book teaches us that there are no limits to what we can achieve, if we are willing to work on ourselves and believe in our potential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Think and Grow Rich&lt;/em&gt; is not just a book, but a real manual for transforming your life. Napoleon Hill shows us that success is a matter of mindset, goals and constant action. An essential read for anyone who wants to improve, grow and realize their dreams.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Who&#39;s Simone Mattioli ?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/01_home/simone-mattioli/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:31:32 +0100</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/01_home/simone-mattioli/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/01_home/simone-mattioli/home.jpeg" alt="Featured image of post Who&#39;s Simone Mattioli ?" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;personal-life&#34;&gt;Personal Life
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;early-days&#34;&gt;Early Days
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/01_home/simone-mattioli/rabbi.JPG&#34;
	width=&#34;2272&#34;
	height=&#34;1704&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/01_home/simone-mattioli/rabbi_hu14685709377490570549.JPG 480w, http://localhost:1313/01_home/simone-mattioli/rabbi_hu17811461578758323397.JPG 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Me when I was a child in Val di Rabbi&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;133&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;320px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was born in the little town of Rovereto, on 28 July 2003 in Italy, nestled in Trentino-Alto Adige, Italy. Since my earliest years, I’ve been passionate about technology, vehicles, and sports that fuel my curiosity, drive, and creativity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-context&#34;&gt;The context
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/01_home/simone-mattioli/biking.JPG&#34;
	width=&#34;3872&#34;
	height=&#34;2592&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/01_home/simone-mattioli/biking_hu2896599252437205521.JPG 480w, http://localhost:1313/01_home/simone-mattioli/biking_hu157065150373252668.JPG 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Me super happy with my first mountain bike&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;149&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;358px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Growing up surrounded by the natural beauty and rich culture of Northern Italy, I found myself drawn to the mechanics of how things work, from engines to computers. My passion for technology started young and has only grown over the years, inspiring me to learn and explore more every day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thanks for joining me on this journey and I suggest you to watch the other pages of this website so maybe you can find something useful there!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;education&#34;&gt;Education
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;itt-marconi-rovereto&#34;&gt;ITT Marconi Rovereto
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/01_home/simone-mattioli/marconi.JPG&#34;
	width=&#34;1024&#34;
	height=&#34;768&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/01_home/simone-mattioli/marconi_hu9519866755300478972.JPG 480w, http://localhost:1313/01_home/simone-mattioli/marconi_hu1079026344971469281.JPG 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;My Last Day of High School&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;133&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;320px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My educational journey began at ITT Marconi in Rovereto, where I discovered my passion for computer science and technology. This prestigious institution provided a strong foundation in technical subjects, enabling me to explore various aspects of computing while honing my analytical and problem-solving skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At ITT Marconi, I was immersed in a curriculum that balanced theory with practical application. Courses in programming, computer networks, and electronics sparked my interest and challenged me to think critically about how technology influences our daily lives. The hands-on projects and collaborative environment encouraged me to work alongside my peers, fostering teamwork and communication skills that are essential in today’s tech landscape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond the classroom, ITT Marconi offered a variety of extracurricular activities, including coding clubs and competitions, which further fueled my enthusiasm for technology. These experiences solidified my decision to pursue a Bachelor’s degree in Computer Science and laid the groundwork for my future studies at the University of Verona. I am grateful for the education I received at ITT Marconi, as it played a pivotal role in shaping my academic and professional aspirations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;bachelor-degree-in-computer-science&#34;&gt;Bachelor Degree in Computer Science
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/01_home/simone-mattioli/verona.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;848&#34;
	height=&#34;240&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/01_home/simone-mattioli/verona_hu15599915847678307440.jpg 480w, http://localhost:1313/01_home/simone-mattioli/verona_hu8275353217975971706.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;University Of Verona&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;353&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;848px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m currently pursuing a Bachelor’s degree in Computer Science at the University of Verona, an exciting chapter in my life that combines my long-standing passion for technology with hands-on learning and problem-solving. The program challenges me to deepen my understanding of computing principles, from algorithms and data structures to artificial intelligence and software development, while also encouraging a mindset for innovation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Studying in Verona, a city rich in history and culture, adds a unique layer to my academic experience. Here, I’m part of a vibrant student community, collaborating on projects, learning from experienced professors, and gaining insights into how technology impacts various fields. This degree is more than just a pathway to a career—it’s a journey that’s shaping my skills, thinking, and goals. Each course and project brings me closer to building a future where I can apply my knowledge to make a difference in the tech world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;continuous-learning&#34;&gt;Continuous Learning
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m super passionate about learning new stuff, as I know that you can&amp;rsquo;t know enough&amp;hellip;
One argoument that really interest me is &lt;strong&gt;business&lt;/strong&gt; and the related topic around this umbrella term as I already know that I don&amp;rsquo;t wanna do the employee in my life but I wanna create something mine &amp;amp; big.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For creating that I need to develop a lots of skills such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Marketing&lt;/strong&gt; because you can be the best in your fild but if nobody knows you, how can the customer reach your solution?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Economics&lt;/strong&gt;, a company need to be in profit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Project &amp;amp; Team Management&lt;/strong&gt; as you need to compleate and reach the milestones and if you want to build something big you can&amp;rsquo;t do it by yourself but you have to be sourrounded by very smart people and you need be also smart managin them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mindset&lt;/strong&gt; as you need to be resilient and ready for everything in this game.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this are the most things that I study in my leasure time&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;listen-to-valerios-interview-to-know-more-about-me&#34;&gt;Listen to Valerio&amp;rsquo;s Interview to know more about me
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;video-wrapper&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
            src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/U9V8CkewXEY&#34; 
            allowfullscreen 
            title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;
    &gt;
    &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Birdwatching Experience with SWAROVSKI OPTIK at Le Ali del Frassino Residence (Lake Frassino)</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/frassino/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/frassino/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/frassino/invito.png" alt="Featured image of post Birdwatching Experience with SWAROVSKI OPTIK at Le Ali del Frassino Residence (Lake Frassino)" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/frassino/swarovski.jpeg&#34;
	width=&#34;337&#34;
	height=&#34;150&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/frassino/swarovski_hu14759465543953173956.jpeg 480w, http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/frassino/swarovski_hu6023009479089032581.jpeg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Logo Swarovski Optik&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;224&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;539px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, thanks to my project &lt;em&gt;Mountain Fauna Lover&lt;/em&gt;, I had the chance to participate in an exclusive event organized by SWAROVSKI OPTIK Italy at the stunning Frassino Oasis in Peschiera del Garda.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mountain Fauna Lover&lt;/em&gt; began almost as a joke, born from my love for mountains and wildlife. I never imagined it would open doors to such exciting collaborations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/frassino/migrazione.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1200&#34;
	height=&#34;800&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/frassino/migrazione_hu3415763475070476929.jpg 480w, http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/frassino/migrazione_hu15628709650227752216.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Bird Migration&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;150&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;360px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through this project, I’ve been able to experience nature up close, often alongside experts and using top-tier equipment, making each adventure more unforgettable than the last.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/frassino/papera.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;3339&#34;
	height=&#34;2506&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/frassino/papera_hu12033954271459282994.jpg 480w, http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/frassino/papera_hu12014715791681049840.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Duck Photo&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;133&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;319px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time, we were immersed in an extraordinary birdwatching experience with expert guidance and SWAROVSKI OPTIK’s impressive tools, including the NL X52 binoculars and the BTX spotting scope. The day began with a presentation by SWAROVSKI OPTIK Italy’s manager, Franco Cernigliaro, and ornithologist Alessandro Sartori, who introduced us to the bird species we’d encounter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/frassino/binocolo.JPG&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;900&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/frassino/binocolo_hu8836717783631905540.JPG 480w, http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/frassino/binocolo_hu7288733104192064040.JPG 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;New Swarovski Optik NL-Pures Series&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;213&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;512px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During my meeting with Franco Cernigliaro, the Country Manager of Swarovski Optik Italy, we exchanged inspiring ideas and perspectives on biodiversity and sustainability. It was a remarkable experience to engage with someone equally dedicated to nature and innovation. Our discussion centered on how these themes are fundamental to Swarovski’s mission—not just as marketing strategies but as true core values.
Swarovski Optik actively encourages deeper connections with nature and is committed to supporting sustainable practices and environmentally responsible technologies in their high-precision optics products&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/frassino/pool.JPG&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1080&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/frassino/pool_hu480610701872245088.JPG 480w, http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/frassino/pool_hu5052254301236937194.JPG 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Ali del Frassino Hotel&amp;rsquo;s Pool&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The observation was incredible—Red-crested Pochards, Tufted Ducks, Teals, and, with a bit of luck, a Marsh Harrier—all appeared in their full beauty, enhanced by the sharpness and clarity of SWAROVSKI’s optics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project has allowed me to build connections with companies like SWAROVSKI OPTIK and explore the world of wildlife in inspiring ways. Who knows what the future holds for &lt;em&gt;Mountain Fauna Lover&lt;/em&gt;… perhaps it will grow from a simple passion into something even greater. Stay tuned for more adventures!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Don Mazza College</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/mazza/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/mazza/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/mazza/max.png" alt="Featured image of post Don Mazza College" /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spiegare come l&amp;rsquo;ho trovato&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;come mi sono trovato&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;linkare il mio video &amp;ldquo;recensione&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Esperienze fatte:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;conoscenza di persone ( poche, 1 -&amp;gt; Vale )&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Condivisione&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ore formative&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Viaggio di Budapest&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Confronto con gli altri coetanei&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>EPICURE Hackathon GPU - October 2024</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/03_projects/epicure-hackathon-2024/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/03_projects/epicure-hackathon-2024/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/03_projects/epicure-hackathon-2024/cover.jpg" alt="Featured image of post EPICURE Hackathon GPU - October 2024" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;EPICURE Hackathon&lt;/strong&gt;, held from October 28-31, 2024, brought together developers, researchers, and enthusiasts from across Europe to dive deep into the world of &lt;strong&gt;GPU programming and high-performance computing (HPC)&lt;/strong&gt;. This event was hosted in collaboration with &lt;strong&gt;CINECA&lt;/strong&gt;, one of the leading HPC centers in Europe, renowned for its contributions to scientific computing and advanced research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hackathon was meticulously structured, featuring both hands-on labs and theoretical sessions, designed to empower participants with the latest skills in &lt;strong&gt;CUDA programming&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;OpenACC&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;GPU optimization techniques&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-1-getting-started-with-gpu-computing&#34;&gt;Day 1: Getting Started with GPU Computing
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The first day served as an introduction to GPU computing, aimed at setting a strong foundation. Topics included:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction to GPU Computing:&lt;/strong&gt; A look into the architecture and advantages of using GPUs for high-performance tasks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CUDA Basics:&lt;/strong&gt; Practical insights into CUDA, NVIDIA&amp;rsquo;s parallel computing platform, providing a gateway to harnessing the power of GPU cores.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The agenda for Day 1 was as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;th&gt;Time&lt;/th&gt;
          &lt;th&gt;Session&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;9:00 - 9:15&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Welcome and Registration&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;9:15 - 9:30&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;EPICURE HPC Application Support for EuroHPC Users&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;9:30 - 10:30&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Introduction to GPU Computing&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;10:30 - 11:00&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Coffee Break&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;11:00 - 12:30&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Introduction to CUDA&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;12:30 - 14:00&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Lunch&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;14:00 - 15:30&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;OpenACC Programming and Profiling with Nsight&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;15:30 - 16:00&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Coffee Break&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;16:00 - 17:30&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;OpenACC Programming and Profiling with Nsight&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Images from Day 1:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/03_projects/epicure-hackathon-2024/1.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;8064&#34;
	height=&#34;6048&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/03_projects/epicure-hackathon-2024/1_hu9058614684240352447.jpg 480w, http://localhost:1313/03_projects/epicure-hackathon-2024/1_hu2407595864030796957.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Theory Part: Introduction to CUDA and GPU Programming&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;133&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;320px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-2-advanced-gpu-optimization-and-profiling&#34;&gt;Day 2: Advanced GPU Optimization and Profiling
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Day 2 took things to the next level, focusing on &lt;strong&gt;advanced GPU optimization and profiling techniques&lt;/strong&gt;. Participants were guided through various optimization methods to fine-tune GPU applications, reducing computation time and maximizing efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;th&gt;Time&lt;/th&gt;
          &lt;th&gt;Session&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;9:00 - 10:30&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Advanced GPU Optimization and Profiling&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;10:30 - 11:00&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Coffee Break&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;11:00 - 12:30&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Advanced GPU Optimization and Profiling (Continued)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;12:30 - 14:00&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Lunch&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;14:00 - 17:30&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Lab Session (with your code or a provided code)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hands-on lab in the afternoon provided an opportunity to implement what we learned using real-world examples, supported by the CINECA team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-3-4-intensive-lab-sessions&#34;&gt;Day 3-4: Intensive Lab Sessions
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The last two days were dedicated to &lt;strong&gt;intensive lab sessions&lt;/strong&gt;. Participants worked on challenging GPU computing projects, with mentors available to provide guidance and feedback. These sessions enabled us to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Test and debug our code using real-time feedback from experts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Engage in peer-to-peer learning, exchanging ideas and optimizing our implementations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Utilize &lt;strong&gt;Nsight&lt;/strong&gt; and other profiling tools to analyze performance and identify bottlenecks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;th&gt;Date&lt;/th&gt;
          &lt;th&gt;Morning (9:00 - 12:30)&lt;/th&gt;
          &lt;th&gt;Afternoon (14:00 - 17:30)&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;October 30&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Lab Session&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Lab Session&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;October 31&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Lab Session&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Lab Session&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;key-takeaways&#34;&gt;Key Takeaways
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This hackathon was more than just a technical event; it was a community-building experience. Here are some of the main takeaways:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Networking:&lt;/strong&gt; I had the opportunity to connect with like-minded individuals passionate about GPU programming and HPC.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learning New Tools:&lt;/strong&gt; From CUDA basics to advanced profiling with &lt;strong&gt;Nsight&lt;/strong&gt;, I gained hands-on experience with cutting-edge tools.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Real-World Problem Solving:&lt;/strong&gt; The projects and examples we tackled were grounded in real-world applications, highlighting the impact of GPU acceleration in domains like scientific research, machine learning, and data analysis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;final-thoughts&#34;&gt;Final Thoughts
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reflecting on these four days, I feel a renewed enthusiasm for &lt;strong&gt;GPU computing&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;HPC&lt;/strong&gt;. The skills I gained, combined with the amazing people I met, made this hackathon an unforgettable experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interested in learning more? Check out the links below to access more details on EPICURE events, a recap video, and the GitHub repository with sample codes used during the hackathon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Links&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://epicure-hpc.eu&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;EPICURE HPC Event Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EPICURE_hackathon2024&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Event Recap Video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/EPICURE-hackathon-2024/sample-codes&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;GitHub Repository of Sample Codes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://gitlab.hpc.cineca.it/training/epicure-gpu-hackathon.git&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;GitLab GPU Repository&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://hackmd.io/@epicurehack/r1qTnKXgyl&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;HackMD Hackathon Document&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://hackmd.io/rEH9zDu1RAK4xhwNrBVpKA?view&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;My HackMD Project Document&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This hackathon has certainly sparked a deeper interest in exploring the potential of GPUs for high-performance tasks. I’m looking forward to applying these skills in future projects and sharing my insights with the community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/03_projects/epicure-hackathon-2024/3.jpeg&#34;
	width=&#34;2966&#34;
	height=&#34;1674&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/03_projects/epicure-hackathon-2024/3_hu4568767519802119854.jpeg 480w, http://localhost:1313/03_projects/epicure-hackathon-2024/3_hu7805776666760800763.jpeg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Me Presenting our results of the Lab sessions of the two days before&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;425px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;youtube-vlogs&#34;&gt;YouTube Vlogs
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve made some mini vlogs about my experience in Bologna during this event and this is the first of the playlist
&lt;div class=&#34;video-wrapper&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
            src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/fnzTTCAioHk&#34; 
            allowfullscreen 
            title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;
    &gt;
    &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Volounteering Activity in Brazil</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/brazil/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/brazil/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/brazil/Happy.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Volounteering Activity in Brazil" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/brazil/don-mazza-pia.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;600&#34;
	height=&#34;304&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/brazil/don-mazza-pia_hu13757114917089963455.jpg 480w, http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/brazil/don-mazza-pia_hu7487483930222575544.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Don Mazza Logo&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;197&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;473px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My volunteer experience in Brazil was an unforgettable journey that led me to discover not only a country rich in culture, but also the daily challenges faced by people in vulnerable situations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We left in seven, a heterogeneous group composed of six strangers from different Italian cities: Verona, Padua and Rome. The experience was organized by &lt;strong&gt;Collegio Di Merito Don Mazza&lt;/strong&gt;, an institution that promotes social commitment and volunteering as well as providing accommodation for university students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-cities-visited&#34;&gt;The Cities Visited
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;During our stay, we had the opportunity to explore different areas of Brazil, focusing mainly on Recife and João Pessoa, the largest cities we visited, before heading inland to Zumbi and Itapororoca. These cities are a vibrant mix of culture, history and traditions, but also of social challenges that have deeply affected us since our arrival.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;significant-moments&#34;&gt;Significant Moments
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;It would be impossible to remember them all since the experience was characterized by moments of joy and just as many of emotional difficulty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/brazil/food.jpeg&#34;
	width=&#34;4032&#34;
	height=&#34;3024&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/brazil/food_hu1004313580069494144.jpeg 480w, http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/brazil/food_hu7872106298772268378.jpeg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Serving Food in Itapororoca&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;133&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;320px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most touching memories was when we distributed food to people in need, an act that made us realize the critical reality in which many communities lived.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also visited the communities of &lt;strong&gt;Olinda&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Alto do Mateus&lt;/strong&gt;, where we saw up close the precarious living conditions of the local people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/brazil/1.png&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1080&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/brazil/1_hu1494336940421190946.png 480w, http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/brazil/1_hu10514475447556642522.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;alto do mateus ( João Pessoa )&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/brazil/2.png&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1080&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/brazil/2_hu10684382541712246701.png 480w, http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/brazil/2_hu6112649909584375486.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Brazil differences ( poor &amp; rich side )&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;itapororoca-vibes&#34;&gt;Itapororoca Vibes
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/brazil/escola.JPG&#34;
	width=&#34;2000&#34;
	height=&#34;900&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/brazil/escola_hu9967466731122662437.JPG 480w, http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/brazil/escola_hu15638584843371399879.JPG 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Visiting the project at Itapororoca ( first day )&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;222&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;533px&#34;
	
&gt;
In Itapororoca, we were hosted by an extraordinary family who dedicated their lives to creating a school and providing aid to the local community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/brazil/itapororoca.jpeg&#34;
	width=&#34;4032&#34;
	height=&#34;3024&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/brazil/itapororoca_hu15076894320659152668.jpeg 480w, http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/brazil/itapororoca_hu14873090201789822252.jpeg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Preparation for the Carneval at Itapororoca ( second day )&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;133&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;320px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had the opportunity to meet each member of their family, wonderful people who welcomed us with unprecedented openness and hospitality, which deeply touched me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/brazil/itapororoca.JPG&#34;
	width=&#34;4032&#34;
	height=&#34;3024&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/brazil/itapororoca_hu14734203814576052921.JPG 480w, http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/brazil/itapororoca_hu18434290852694748873.JPG 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;itapororoca host large Family&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;133&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;320px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The moment of saying goodbye was extremely difficult, as the bond that had been created was sincere and deep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/brazil/itapororocaFamily.jpeg&#34;
	width=&#34;4032&#34;
	height=&#34;3024&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/brazil/itapororocaFamily_hu5549875887473092507.jpeg 480w, http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/brazil/itapororocaFamily_hu1982609080503288054.jpeg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;itapororoca host family party&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;133&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;320px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, thanks to technology, we are still able to stay in touch, sharing moments and memories that unite us despite the distance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/brazil/triglia.JPG&#34;
	width=&#34;4032&#34;
	height=&#34;3024&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/brazil/triglia_hu13112908762323549975.JPG 480w, http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/brazil/triglia_hu13812376625019430941.JPG 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;itapororoca nature walk&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;133&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;320px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;beira-da-linha-project&#34;&gt;Beira da Linha Project
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/brazil/beiraTogether.jpeg&#34;
	width=&#34;4032&#34;
	height=&#34;3024&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/brazil/beiraTogether_hu827412341431818347.jpeg 480w, http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/brazil/beiraTogether_hu12219629092561136464.jpeg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Beira da Linha Project with child&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;133&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;320px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without a doubt, my favorite project was &lt;strong&gt;Beira da Linha&lt;/strong&gt;. Here we assisted teachers in their lessons and I had the opportunity to interact with children and young people who attended after-school activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/brazil/beihra.jpeg&#34;
	width=&#34;4032&#34;
	height=&#34;3024&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/brazil/beihra_hu7243505683530460084.jpeg 480w, http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/brazil/beihra_hu7325021660530492723.jpeg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Beira da Linha Project timeout&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;133&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;320px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These young people, coming from difficult backgrounds, aspired to a better future, and my bond with them was extraordinary. The possibility of contributing to their educational journey was one of the most rewarding experiences of my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/brazil/organizers.jpeg&#34;
	width=&#34;5712&#34;
	height=&#34;4284&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/brazil/organizers_hu14435325769428591544.jpeg 480w, http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/brazil/organizers_hu2952270892498039134.jpeg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Beira da Linha Project with organizers&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;133&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;320px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And my greatest respect goes to these educators who dedicate their lives to improving that of the new generations&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/brazil/Football.JPG&#34;
	width=&#34;3840&#34;
	height=&#34;2160&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/brazil/Football_hu5399341690104687459.JPG 480w, http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/brazil/Football_hu17750036120901041899.JPG 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Beira da Linha Project bare foot football&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During our stay there, as a tradition in Brazil, we played football a lot&amp;hellip;but the difference was that we were all playing barefoot on the concrete since they only had one pair of shoes, or sometimes not even those and therefore they couldn&amp;rsquo;t/didn&amp;rsquo;t want to ruin them&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/brazil/boys.jpeg&#34;
	width=&#34;4032&#34;
	height=&#34;3024&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/brazil/boys_hu7284022724489658609.jpeg 480w, http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/brazil/boys_hu1895651406400082243.jpeg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Last photo with my favourite Beira da Linha Project kids&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;133&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;320px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-unique-group&#34;&gt;A Unique Group
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/brazil/all.jpeg&#34;
	width=&#34;5712&#34;
	height=&#34;4284&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/brazil/all_hu16480586880400215249.jpeg 480w, http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/brazil/all_hu12161417594992945143.jpeg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Group at Beira da Linha Project &#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;133&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;320px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The group with which I shared this adventure was also fantastic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/brazil/house.jpeg&#34;
	width=&#34;4032&#34;
	height=&#34;3024&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/brazil/house_hu799592298550650950.jpeg 480w, http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/brazil/house_hu12717877237641760338.jpeg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;itapororoca host familiy home&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;133&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;320px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hit it off right away, creating bonds that made the experience even more unique and I really have to thank you Noemi, Federica, Maristella, Andrea, Rachid for the amazing experience that we&amp;rsquo;ve made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/brazil/praia.JPG&#34;
	width=&#34;4032&#34;
	height=&#34;3024&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/brazil/praia_hu5767675381758232612.JPG 480w, http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/brazil/praia_hu17250628595730047875.JPG 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Beach of jacarè sunset with Alberto&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;133&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;320px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back home, I can finally reflect on what I experienced and assimilate the messages and lessons learned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three months have passed since I returned, but the emotions and experiences I lived in Brazil continue to influence my daily life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We shared so much in only three weeks and when it comes to my mind it seems like a film&amp;hellip;too good to be true&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/brazil/canyon.jpeg&#34;
	width=&#34;4032&#34;
	height=&#34;3024&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/brazil/canyon_hu2684194006454475023.jpeg 480w, http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/brazil/canyon_hu14008367952669873225.jpeg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Exploring the canyon with Alberto&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;133&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;320px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;contribution-to-projects--mazzian-ideals&#34;&gt;Contribution to Projects / Mazzian Ideals
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have actively participated in volunteer projects organized by &lt;strong&gt;Collegio Don Mazza&lt;/strong&gt;, with particular attention to education and social support initiatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During this experience, I collaborated on projects aimed at improving the socio-educational conditions of children and adolescents in disadvantaged areas, including after-school activities, creative and sports workshops, and literacy programs. I also had the opportunity to contribute to social inclusion and the promotion of the psychophysical well-being of young people, working in an intercultural exchange context that enriched my relational and organizational skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;soft-skills-development&#34;&gt;Soft Skills Development
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This experience has allowed me to develop important soft skills such as teamwork, leadership and problem solving skills. The daily challenges and the need to adapt to a new reality have taught me to collaborate effectively with others and to look for innovative solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;My volunteering experience in Brazil has been a journey of personal and professional growth that I would invite anyone to do, as I recommended during the seminars/meetings of presentation and testimony of the experience that I held together with my fellow adventurers in Rome, Padua and Verona.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would conclude with a phrase that &lt;strong&gt;Nelson Mandela&lt;/strong&gt; once said:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Education is the most powerful weapon you can use.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This phrase perfectly encapsulates the essence of my journey and the meaning of the work we have done and the message that I tried to pass on to these young Brazilians. I hope to continue to carry forward the teachings of this experience and to contribute to the improvement of people&amp;rsquo;s lives, wherever I am.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;here-are-some-more-photos-about-our-stay&#34;&gt;Here are some more photos about our stay
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/brazil/visit.jpeg&#34;
	width=&#34;4032&#34;
	height=&#34;3024&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/brazil/visit_hu6045549713402706096.jpeg 480w, http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/brazil/visit_hu15241846057362320093.jpeg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;itapororoca&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;133&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;320px&#34;
	
&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/brazil/wow.jpeg&#34;
	width=&#34;4032&#34;
	height=&#34;3024&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/brazil/wow_hu1868642336289139639.jpeg 480w, http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/brazil/wow_hu7791958914182014879.jpeg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;itapororoca&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;133&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;320px&#34;
	
&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/brazil/asilo.jpeg&#34;
	width=&#34;4032&#34;
	height=&#34;3024&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/brazil/asilo_hu10841011801382672923.jpeg 480w, http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/brazil/asilo_hu1406425626507380819.jpeg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;itapororoca&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;133&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;320px&#34;
	
&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/brazil/1school.jpeg&#34;
	width=&#34;4032&#34;
	height=&#34;3024&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/brazil/1school_hu7068086369821003238.jpeg 480w, http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/brazil/1school_hu12488817350023253121.jpeg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Group&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;133&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;320px&#34;
	
&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/brazil/school.JPG&#34;
	width=&#34;4032&#34;
	height=&#34;3024&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/brazil/school_hu13132640188473838177.JPG 480w, http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/brazil/school_hu3783253742305201514.JPG 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;itapororoca&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;133&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;320px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;here-a-short-recap-video-about-the-experience&#34;&gt;Here a short recap video about the experience
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;video-wrapper&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
            src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ptVTxfSqaCo&#34; 
            allowfullscreen 
            title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;
    &gt;
    &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>21th birth Day in Brazil</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/21th-birthday/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/21th-birthday/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/21th-birthday/olilnda.JPG" alt="Featured image of post 21th birth Day in Brazil" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;My 21st birthday was unique, an experience I will never forget. I spent it in Brazil, during my volunteering period, far from home and all my loved ones. On that occasion, I was not surrounded by the familiar faces of friends and relatives, but by six strangers, who shared with me the experience of volunteering in a country so different from mine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/21th-birthday/spiaggia.png&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1080&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/21th-birthday/spiaggia_hu671467812281117484.png 480w, http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/21th-birthday/spiaggia_hu8872962511018767721.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Relaxing morning in Olinda beach&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did not expect anything special. Usually, birthdays have never had a particular meaning for me, but that day turned out to be different, special, unique. Celebrating a birthday far from home and loved ones was a first step out of my comfort zone. It allowed me to live the moment with lightness and curiosity, immersed in a new experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;an-unexpected-surprise&#34;&gt;An Unexpected Surprise
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/21th-birthday/us.png&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1080&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/21th-birthday/us_hu2230500589577567921.png 480w, http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/21th-birthday/us_hu2430990538795517930.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;us waiting for Eltom on the seaside&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What made my birthday truly memorable was the surprise that my travel companions organized. They found out only a few days later that I had turned 18, and they decided to surprise me with a surprise that left me speechless. One morning we woke up at 4:30, ready to go and watch the sunrise on the beautiful Brazilian beach of Cabo Branco.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had no idea what to expect. We reached the beach, the sky was starting to turn warm, a prelude to dawn. It was then that they gave me a cake, prepared especially for me. We all shared it together, eating and enjoying the sunrise in one of the most beautiful places I have ever seen and then ending it in style with dinner with Don Eltom and Don Alberto who accompanied us on our volunteer experience in the Northeast of Brazil.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/21th-birthday/dinner.JPG&#34;
	width=&#34;1600&#34;
	height=&#34;900&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/21th-birthday/dinner_hu13942985537764711094.JPG 480w, http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/21th-birthday/dinner_hu14569323355368024075.JPG 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;My Birthday Brazilian Dinner&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-moment-of-pure-happiness&#34;&gt;A Moment of Pure Happiness
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In those moments of simplicity and friendship, I felt truly happy. It was a moment of pure connection, of gratitude towards life and towards these people who, even if they had just met, had made that day special. I realized how precious it was to step out of my patterns and embrace what is new and unexpected that life has to offer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;advice-from-the-heart&#34;&gt;Advice from the Heart
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;If I can give you advice, it is to accept every experience that happens to you, even those that scare you or that seem difficult or &amp;ldquo;not made for you&amp;rdquo;. Those experiences will change you and make you grow. Getting out of your comfort zone, experiencing the world with openness and curiosity: these are the things that will give you unforgettable moments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That birthday away from home, in Brazil, taught me the value of sharing, friendship and adventure. It was an experience that I will always carry in my heart also with the other part of my journey there in Brazil doing volounteering activity&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/21th-birthday/beihra.JPG&#34;
	width=&#34;4032&#34;
	height=&#34;3024&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/21th-birthday/beihra_hu7466839578328914173.JPG 480w, http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/21th-birthday/beihra_hu1391642998245033048.JPG 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;The last day in the Beihra Da Linha Project&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;133&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;320px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>CLab UNIRv</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/03_projects/think/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/03_projects/think/</guid>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;-riqualificazione-della-rocca-di-nogarole-il-nostro-viaggio-con-il-clab-verona&#34;&gt;🚀 Riqualificazione della Rocca di Nogarole: Il nostro viaggio con il CLab Verona
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Il percorso del &lt;strong&gt;Contamination Lab (CLab)&lt;/strong&gt; dell&amp;rsquo;Università di Verona è stato molto più che un semplice progetto: è stata un&amp;rsquo;avventura, una sfida appassionante che ha permesso a me e al mio team di esplorare nuove competenze, affrontare ostacoli reali e soprattutto creare idee concrete per la nostra comunità.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-il-nostro-obiettivo-dare-nuova-vita-alla-rocca-di-nogarole&#34;&gt;🌿 Il nostro obiettivo: Dare nuova vita alla Rocca di Nogarole
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Il cuore della nostra sfida era proporre idee innovative per riqualificare la splendida e storica Rocca di Nogarole. Un monumento simbolo, ricco di storia, che meritava di essere valorizzato per tornare a vivere come centro culturale, sociale e turistico, portando benefici tangibili alla comunità locale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-il-percorso-crescita-innovazione-e-collaborazione&#34;&gt;💡 Il percorso: Crescita, Innovazione e Collaborazione
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Durante questo percorso abbiamo avuto la possibilità di seguire workshop mirati, sessioni di brainstorming guidate da mentor qualificati e incontri con esperti provenienti da diversi settori. Il CLab ci ha insegnato non solo come lavorare in team, ma anche come pensare &amp;ldquo;fuori dagli schemi&amp;rdquo;, affrontando problemi reali con creatività e pragmatismo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In questo articolo troverete:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;📚 Il materiale formativo che ci è stato fornito durante il percorso&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🛠️ Tutto il materiale prodotto dal nostro team durante il progetto (presentazioni, documenti, analisi, ecc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-un-ringraziamento-speciale-al-team&#34;&gt;🎉 Un ringraziamento speciale al Team
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Non posso che ringraziare i miei straordinari compagni di viaggio: ognuno ha contribuito con le proprie idee, competenze ed entusiasmo a rendere unico questo percorso. È stato un vero piacere lavorare al vostro fianco.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/03_projects/think/team.JPG&#34;
	width=&#34;2048&#34;
	height=&#34;1532&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/03_projects/think/team_hu7793195986488237696.JPG 480w, http://localhost:1313/03_projects/think/team_hu13746834898767398606.JPG 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Foto del nostro Team&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;133&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;320px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-una-grande-esperienza-condivisa&#34;&gt;🌟 Una grande esperienza condivisa
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Condivido anche una foto di tutti i partecipanti del CLab Verona: ogni persona in questa foto porta con sé idee, sogni e competenze che potranno cambiare concretamente il nostro futuro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/03_projects/think/tutti.JPG&#34;
	width=&#34;2048&#34;
	height=&#34;1532&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/03_projects/think/tutti_hu10887594215648116625.JPG 480w, http://localhost:1313/03_projects/think/tutti_hu16937088438961584462.JPG 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Foto di tutti i partecipanti&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;133&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;320px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-allegati-e-risorse&#34;&gt;📥 Allegati e Risorse
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Di seguito potete trovare tutto il materiale relativo al nostro progetto e al percorso del CLab, disponibile per chiunque desideri approfondire o trarre ispirazione:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Materiale formativo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Documentazione del progetto finale&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Risultati delle nostre analisi&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grazie per aver visitato questa pagina e per esserti interessato al nostro viaggio. Speriamo che il nostro lavoro possa essere fonte d&amp;rsquo;ispirazione per progetti futuri e per chiunque voglia mettersi in gioco per cambiare le cose concretamente.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;✨ &lt;strong&gt;Continuiamo a innovare insieme!&lt;/strong&gt; ✨&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#CLabVerona #Riqualificazione #RoccaDiNogarole #Innovazione #Crescita #Teamwork&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Mountain Fauna Lover</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/03_projects/mountain-fauna-lover/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/03_projects/mountain-fauna-lover/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/03_projects/mountain-fauna-lover/logo.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Mountain Fauna Lover" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to MountainFaunaLover! Here, I share my passion for nature, wildlife, and the captivating landscapes of mountain regions. On Instagram, you’ll find a curated collection of my favorite moments in the wilderness, from up-close shots of unique wildlife to breathtaking mountain vistas. Each post is a window into my adventures, capturing the serenity, beauty, and diversity of the natural world that inspires me daily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On YouTube, I dive even deeper. My channel is a space for storytelling, featuring video journeys, wildlife encounters, and conservation insights, bringing viewers along on my explorations. Whether you’re a fellow nature enthusiast or just stopping by for some visual serenity, my content on MountainFaunaLover is dedicated to sharing the awe and importance of our wild places. Join me in celebrating the mountains, fauna, and the fascinating stories they hold!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;youtube-spoiler&#34;&gt;YouTube Spoiler
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;video-wrapper&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
            src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ONGaGgr795k&#34; 
            allowfullscreen 
            title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;
    &gt;
    &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Simo Performance Coach Consultant</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/03_projects/performance/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/03_projects/performance/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/03_projects/performance/image.png" alt="Featured image of post Simo Performance Coach Consultant" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;stay-tunedmore-info-are-comming-soon-meanwhile-you-can-contact-me-via-email-for-info&#34;&gt;STAY TUNED&amp;hellip;more info are comming soon, meanwhile you can contact me via email for INFO
&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Simo&#39;s Online &amp; Digital Diary</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/03_projects/home/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/03_projects/home/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/03_projects/home/logo.jpeg" alt="Featured image of post Simo&#39;s Online &amp; Digital Diary" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to simo&amp;rsquo;s Diary, a place where I love to share&amp;hellip;.da completare&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;discover-my-youtube-channel-simos-diary&#34;&gt;Discover My YouTube Channel: Simo&amp;rsquo;s Diary
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today I want to tell you about my YouTube channel, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/@SimosDiary2003&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Simo&amp;rsquo;s Diary&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, where I share moments of my life, personal projects and passions. This space was born from the desire to document my experiences in an authentic and transparent way, showing you trips, adventures and much more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-did-i-create-simos-diary&#34;&gt;Why Did I Create Simo&amp;rsquo;s Diary?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;We live in an era where technology allows us to capture moments in high quality simply with a smartphone. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to waste this opportunity! In fact, I think it&amp;rsquo;s fantastic to be able to record and share pieces of my life that, otherwise, would only remain in memory. With Simo&amp;rsquo;s Diary, not only can I collect these memories for the future, but also share them with anyone who wants to follow them and maybe find inspiration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-youll-find-on-simos-diary&#34;&gt;What You&amp;rsquo;ll Find on Simo&amp;rsquo;s Diary
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;On my channel, you&amp;rsquo;ll find content that tells the &lt;strong&gt;real life&lt;/strong&gt; of an ambitious boy, one who is ready to make sacrifices to achieve his goals. I want to show you the world without filters, far from the perfection we often see online. Through my videos, I will take you with me on journeys, challenges and everyday moments, with the aim of reminding myself and others how important it is to appreciate everything that life offers us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;main-themes&#34;&gt;Main Themes:
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gratitude and Awareness:&lt;/strong&gt; Every experience I share is an opportunity to reflect on what we have and what we can be grateful for.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ambition and Determination:&lt;/strong&gt; Simo&amp;rsquo;s Diary is also the story of a boy who wants a lot from life and is not afraid to fight to make his dreams come true.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Authenticity:&lt;/strong&gt; I am not interested in showing a perfect life, but rather in offering a real image of my existence, with its challenges, difficulties and not just its goals.-&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Personal growth&lt;/strong&gt; My path and thoughts / skills that I have developed during this process&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thoughts&lt;/strong&gt; When a thought comes to mind, or I start a reasoning when possible I start recording so that I can then listen to myself again in the future and understand how I thought at a certain moment in my life&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;an-invitation-to-follow-your-passions&#34;&gt;An Invitation to Follow Your Passions
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;With Simo&amp;rsquo;s Diary, I want to inspire you to live fully and use the resources we have today to create something meaningful. My hope is that my videos can push you to pursue your goals and cultivate gratitude for the little things in life without forgetting the thing that is closest to my heart lately, the fact of &lt;strong&gt;enjoying life&lt;/strong&gt;, therefore living every moment and challenge with a smile and joy because our time on this earth is very limited and it is not worth getting discouraged and living it badly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you like the idea of ​​discovering adventures, authentic reflections and the real life of a boy who chases his dreams, visit my channel and subscribe!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading, and I hope to see you soon among my followers on YouTube!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;stay-in-touch-with-me&#34;&gt;Stay in touch with me
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Follow me on YouTube and social media to stay updated on my adventures and find out more about my life and my projects!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;listen-to-my-story&#34;&gt;Listen to My Story
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you wanna listen to a deeper introduction, a friend of mine decided to interview me&amp;hellip;here down below you can find a lot&amp;rsquo;s of intresting though as well as my story&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video-wrapper&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
            src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/U9V8CkewXEY&#34; 
            allowfullscreen 
            title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;
    &gt;
    &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Search</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/search/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/search/</guid>
        <description></description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
