<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Swarovski on Simone Mattioli</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/tags/swarovski.html</link><description>Recent content in Swarovski on Simone Mattioli</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://simo-hue.github.io/tags/swarovski/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Birdwatching Experience with SWAROVSKI OPTIK at Le Ali del Frassino Residence (Lake Frassino)</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/04_experiences/frassino.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/04_experiences/frassino.html</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img alt="Logo Swarovski Optik" src="https://simo-hue.github.io/04_experiences/frassino/swarovski.jpeg">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recently, thanks to my project &lt;em>Mountain Fauna Lover&lt;/em>, I had the chance to participate in an exclusive event organized by SWAROVSKI OPTIK Italy at the stunning Frassino Oasis in Peschiera del Garda.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Mountain Fauna Lover&lt;/em> began almost as a joke, born from my love for mountains and wildlife. I never imagined it would open doors to such exciting collaborations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img alt="Bird Migration" src="https://simo-hue.github.io/04_experiences/frassino/migrazione.jpg">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Through this project, I’ve been able to experience nature up close, often alongside experts and using top-tier equipment, making each adventure more unforgettable than the last.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mountain Fauna Lover</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/03_projects/mountain-fauna-lover.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/03_projects/mountain-fauna-lover.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Welcome to MountainFaunaLover! Here, I share my passion for nature, wildlife, and the captivating landscapes of mountain regions. On Instagram, you’ll find a curated collection of my favorite moments in the wilderness, from up-close shots of unique wildlife to breathtaking mountain vistas. Each post is a window into my adventures, capturing the serenity, beauty, and diversity of the natural world that inspires me daily.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On YouTube, I dive even deeper. My channel is a space for storytelling, featuring video journeys, wildlife encounters, and conservation insights, bringing viewers along on my explorations. Whether you’re a fellow nature enthusiast or just stopping by for some visual serenity, my content on MountainFaunaLover is dedicated to sharing the awe and importance of our wild places. Join me in celebrating the mountains, fauna, and the fascinating stories they hold!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>