<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Intelligence on Simone Mattioli</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/tags/intelligence/</link><description>Recent content in Intelligence on Simone Mattioli</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://simo-hue.github.io/tags/intelligence/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Relationship Importance</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/02_thought/relationship/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/02_thought/relationship/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="friendship-and-love">Friendship and Love&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Human relationships are the fundamental pillar of our existence, it is no coincidence that it is said that man is a social animal&amp;hellip; Friendships, family ties and romantic relationships contribute to defining not only the quality of our life, but also who we are and what we can become. We cannot ignore the enormous impact that these connections have on us, for better or for worse, and on our lives.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Daniele Cassioli</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/02_thought/cassioli/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/02_thought/cassioli/</guid><description>&lt;p>I had the privilege of meeting Daniele Cassioli, and I can say that it was a deeply enriching experience. For those who don&amp;rsquo;t know him, Daniele is a blind Paralympic athlete, world champion in water skiing, author and motivational speaker. His story is an extraordinary example of how to transform difficulties into opportunities, and his way of life is a lesson that leads to reflection.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="gratitude-for-opportunities">Gratitude for Opportunities&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Being a student at the Collegio di Merito Don Mazza in Verona is an opportunity that has allowed me to participate in significant events like this. Meetings like this are precious opportunities to grow and look at the world with different eyes. I can only be grateful for everything that this college offers me, not only in terms of training, but also in terms of inspiration and awareness.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Don't Brag</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/02_thought/humility/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/02_thought/humility/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="the-importance-of-humility-but-without-losing-self-confidence">The importance of humility, but without losing self-confidence&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Humility is one of the most appreciated and sought-after qualities, both in personal and professional life. Being humble helps us grow, learn from others and recognize that we do not always have all the answers. It allows us to approach people with respect, creating authentic relationships based on mutual esteem. But it is important to remember that, like all virtues, humility must also be cultivated with balance.
&lt;img src="https://simo-hue.github.io/02_thought/humility/napkin-selection-4.png" alt="">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>History importance</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/02_thought/history/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/02_thought/history/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="my-journey-from-hater-to-curious">My Journey from Hater to Curious&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>I admit that history was my nemesis during my school years. When the professor entered the classroom and started talking about dates, battles and rulers, I felt lost. It all seemed so boring and distant from my reality. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t perceive the value of that knowledge: why on earth would I be interested in what had happened centuries ago?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Over the years, however, something changed. I began to realize my gaps, feeling ashamed of how little I knew about our past (not with others but with myself). I understood that ignoring history was not only an academic shortcoming, but a real limitation in understanding the world around me.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>repetition is the mother of all skills</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/02_thought/repetition/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/02_thought/repetition/</guid><description>&lt;p>There’s a timeless truth in the saying, &lt;em>“Repetition is the mother of all skills.”&lt;/em> It’s something I’ve come to embrace fully since I integrated a method that has completely transformed the way I learn and internalize concepts: &lt;strong>the immersion method&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="what-is-the-immersion-method">What is the Immersion Method?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The immersion method is exactly what it sounds like—a full, deep dive into the subject or skill you want to master. Instead of just skimming the surface or approaching learning sporadically, immersion means surrounding yourself with the material, over and over again, until it becomes second nature. It’s not just about repetition but also about consistency and engagement.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>