<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Intelligence on Simone Mattioli</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/tags/intelligence.html</link><description>Recent content in Intelligence on Simone Mattioli</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://simo-hue.github.io/tags/intelligence/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Daniele Cassioli</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/02_thought/cassioli.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/02_thought/cassioli.html</guid><description>&lt;p>Essere grato per essere nel collegio di merito don mazza di verona e per le opportunità che mi venogo fornite da questo collegio&lt;/p>
&lt;p>parlare della fonazione ( &lt;a href="https://www.danielecassioli.it">https://www.danielecassioli.it&lt;/a> )&lt;/p>
&lt;p>consapevolezza piu profonda dei normodotati&lt;/p>
&lt;p>doti che ha sviluppato&lt;/p>
&lt;p>importanza di saper ironizzare i propri difetti, sfortune per vivere una vita più serena ed impace con se stessi&lt;/p>
&lt;p>dei suoi libri ( uno che ho letto )&lt;/p>
&lt;p>del quanto fare sport sia importante per il benessere e la felicità di una persona&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Don't Brag</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/02_thought/humility.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/02_thought/humility.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="the-importance-of-humility-but-without-losing-self-confidence">The importance of humility, but without losing self-confidence&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Humility is one of the most appreciated and sought-after qualities, both in personal and professional life. Being humble helps us grow, learn from others and recognize that we do not always have all the answers. It allows us to approach people with respect, creating authentic relationships based on mutual esteem. But it is important to remember that, like all virtues, humility must also be cultivated with balance.
&lt;img src="https://simo-hue.github.io/02_thought/humility/napkin-selection-4.png">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>History importance</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/02_thought/history.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/02_thought/history.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="my-journey-from-hater-to-curious">My Journey from Hater to Curious&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>I admit that history was my nemesis during my school years. When the professor entered the classroom and started talking about dates, battles and rulers, I felt lost. It all seemed so boring and distant from my reality. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t perceive the value of that knowledge: why on earth would I be interested in what had happened centuries ago?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Over the years, however, something changed. I began to realize my gaps, feeling ashamed of how little I knew about our past (not with others but with myself). I understood that ignoring history was not only an academic shortcoming, but a real limitation in understanding the world around me.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>repetition is the mother of all skills</title><link>https://simo-hue.github.io/02_thought/repetition.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://simo-hue.github.io/02_thought/repetition.html</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="the-importance-of-repetition">The importance of repetition&lt;/h1></description></item></channel></rss>