<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Success on Simone Mattioli</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/success.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Success on Simone Mattioli</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/success/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t Brag</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/02_thought/humility.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/02_thought/humility.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-importance-of-humility-but-without-losing-self-confidence&#34;&gt;The importance of humility, but without losing self-confidence&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Humility is one of the most appreciated and sought-after qualities, both in personal and professional life. Being humble helps us grow, learn from others and recognize that we do not always have all the answers. It allows us to approach people with respect, creating authentic relationships based on mutual esteem. But it is important to remember that, like all virtues, humility must also be cultivated with balance.&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/02_thought/humility/napkin-selection-4.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>repetition is the mother of all skills</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/02_thought/repetition.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/02_thought/repetition.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There’s a timeless truth in the saying, &lt;em&gt;“Repetition is the mother of all skills.”&lt;/em&gt; It’s something I’ve come to embrace fully since I integrated a method that has completely transformed the way I learn and internalize concepts: &lt;strong&gt;the immersion method&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-the-immersion-method&#34;&gt;What is the Immersion Method?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The immersion method is exactly what it sounds like—a full, deep dive into the subject or skill you want to master. Instead of just skimming the surface or approaching learning sporadically, immersion means surrounding yourself with the material, over and over again, until it becomes second nature. It’s not just about repetition but also about consistency and engagement.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Personal Growth</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/05_passions/persona-growth.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:31:32 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/05_passions/persona-growth.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;as&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/05_passions/persona-growth/personalgrowth.jpg&#34;&gt;&#xA;Embark on a journey of &lt;strong&gt;personal growth&lt;/strong&gt; and self-discovery! This blog is all about transforming life, one article, one book, and one action at a time. Starting with a simple curiosity, I dove into the world of personal development, reading about habits, resilience, mindfulness, and purpose. Each insight led to real changes in how I see myself, set goals, and make decisions. Here, I’ll share lessons from books and articles that have had the biggest impact on my life, along with actionable tips and reflections on the changes I’ve experienced. Join me in exploring the power of intentional self-improvement and see how small shifts can lead to profound personal transformation&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
