<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Success on Simone Mattioli</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/success.html</link>
        <description>Recent content in Success on Simone Mattioli</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/success/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Don&#39;t Brag</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/02_thought/humility.html</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/02_thought/humility.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/02_thought/humility/image.png" alt="Featured image of post Don&#39;t Brag" /&gt;&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-importance-of-humility-but-without-losing-self-confidence&#34;&gt;The importance of humility, but without losing self-confidence
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Humility is one of the most appreciated and sought-after qualities, both in personal and professional life. Being humble helps us grow, learn from others and recognize that we do not always have all the answers. It allows us to approach people with respect, creating authentic relationships based on mutual esteem. But it is important to remember that, like all virtues, humility must also be cultivated with balance.
&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/02_thought/humility/napkin-selection-4.png&#34;
	width=&#34;3888&#34;
	height=&#34;2238&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/02_thought/humility/napkin-selection-4_hu8802562197474333218.png 480w, http://localhost:1313/02_thought/humility/napkin-selection-4_hu17024578509287882581.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;173&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;416px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;when-humility-becomes-a-limit&#34;&gt;When humility becomes a limit
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, there is an insidious risk that hides behind excessive humility. While on the one hand it can be a sign of maturity and wisdom, on the other it can turn into a trap that undermines self-confidence. Being excessively humble can lead to underestimating one&amp;rsquo;s abilities, to belittling one&amp;rsquo;s successes or even to avoiding opportunities for fear of not being &amp;ldquo;enough&amp;rdquo; to face them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a world where comparing ourselves to others is the order of the day, it is easy to fall into the trap of thinking that humility means self-deprecation or extreme modesty. But being humble does not mean belittling yourself, but rather recognizing your limits without losing sight of your strengths. Humility must coexist with a healthy dose of self-esteem.
&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/02_thought/humility/napkin-selection-2.png&#34;
	width=&#34;4104&#34;
	height=&#34;3816&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/02_thought/humility/napkin-selection-2_hu3136251062340009860.png 480w, http://localhost:1313/02_thought/humility/napkin-selection-2_hu10690465949415309701.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;107&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;258px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cultivating-a-balance-humility-and-self-confidence&#34;&gt;Cultivating a balance: Humility and Self-Confidence
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The ideal balance consists of recognizing your own value without falling into arrogance. We can be aware of our skills, celebrating successes with gratitude but without turning them into vanity. We must learn to recognize what we have achieved without feeling superior to others, but also without belittling our path.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To achieve this balance, it is useful to ask yourself: &amp;ldquo;Am I rejecting this recognition because I am truly humble, or because I do not believe in myself enough?&amp;rdquo; Cultivating self-confidence does not mean becoming arrogant, but having the awareness of your own abilities to confidently face challenges and goals.
&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/02_thought/humility/napkin-selection-3.png&#34;
	width=&#34;4969&#34;
	height=&#34;3573&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/02_thought/humility/napkin-selection-3_hu9076800383919372593.png 480w, http://localhost:1313/02_thought/humility/napkin-selection-3_hu10908590416667283626.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;139&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;333px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-conclusion&#34;&gt;In Conclusion
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Humility and self-confidence are not conflicting qualities, but two sides of the same coin. Being humble keeps us grounded in reality, but having self-confidence pushes us to dream bigger and face challenges without fear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Humility does not consist in thinking less of yourself, but in thinking less of yourself.” – &lt;em&gt;C.S. Lewis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/02_thought/humility/napkin-selectiona.png&#34;
	width=&#34;3528&#34;
	height=&#34;1728&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/02_thought/humility/napkin-selectiona_hu2986713959833747791.png 480w, http://localhost:1313/02_thought/humility/napkin-selectiona_hu7098780543284844094.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;204&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;490px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>repetition is the mother of all skills</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/02_thought/repetition.html</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/02_thought/repetition.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/02_thought/repetition/i.png" alt="Featured image of post repetition is the mother of all skills" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;There’s a timeless truth in the saying, &lt;em&gt;“Repetition is the mother of all skills.”&lt;/em&gt; It’s something I’ve come to embrace fully since I integrated a method that has completely transformed the way I learn and internalize concepts: &lt;strong&gt;the immersion method&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-the-immersion-method&#34;&gt;What is the Immersion Method?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The immersion method is exactly what it sounds like—a full, deep dive into the subject or skill you want to master. Instead of just skimming the surface or approaching learning sporadically, immersion means surrounding yourself with the material, over and over again, until it becomes second nature. It’s not just about repetition but also about consistency and engagement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s how I applied it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Daily Exposure&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I made sure to interact with the concepts every single day. Whether it was listening to a podcast, reading a book, taking notes, or even talking about it with others, I created a constant feedback loop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Active Repetition&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Instead of passively consuming material, I actively revisited it. For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I reread the same books multiple times. Each read revealed something I missed the first time or offered new insights as my understanding deepened.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I rewrote my notes. This process helped reinforce the key points in my mind.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Practical Application&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Immersion wasn’t just theoretical. I put what I learned into practice in real-world scenarios, which solidified the knowledge in my subconscious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;from-subconscious-absorption-to-visible-results&#34;&gt;From Subconscious Absorption to Visible Results
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The most incredible change I experienced was seeing how concepts that once felt elusive started to flow naturally. It’s as if they had seeped into my subconscious. I no longer had to think so hard to recall them; they were just &lt;em&gt;there&lt;/em&gt;, ready for use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, while studying personal development topics, I found that principles I’d been exposed to for weeks suddenly became part of my decision-making process. I didn’t have to remind myself to “stay present” or “focus on the process” anymore—it just happened. This transformation wasn’t magic; it was immersion at work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-repetition-is-crucial&#34;&gt;Why Repetition is Crucial
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Repetition isn’t boring; it’s foundational. Every time you revisit a concept:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You &lt;strong&gt;strengthen the neural pathways&lt;/strong&gt; in your brain, making recall faster and easier.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You see new perspectives that weren’t apparent the first time. A single read-through of a book or course can’t uncover all its wisdom.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s what I’ve learned about the power of repetition:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Books are meant to be reread.&lt;/strong&gt; Some of my favorite books have been revisited three or four times, and each time I gain new insights or reinforce old ones.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learning never stops.&lt;/strong&gt; What seems redundant often turns out to be the foundation for mastery.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-impact-of-immersion-on-me&#34;&gt;The Impact of Immersion on Me
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The immersion method has had a profound effect on my growth, both personally and professionally. Not only have I seen results in terms of knowledge retention, but also in how I think and act. Concepts that I struggled to grasp now feel second nature, and my confidence has skyrocketed because I trust in the process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;final-thoughts-repetition-as-a-way-of-life&#34;&gt;Final Thoughts: Repetition as a Way of Life
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a world obsessed with novelty, we often undervalue repetition. But true mastery isn’t about skimming through countless books or ideas; it’s about deeply understanding and integrating a few. Immersion and repetition are how you turn knowledge into action and action into habits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, let me leave you with this:&lt;br&gt;
Revisit that book you love. Redo that course you enjoyed. Practice that skill over and over. You might be surprised by how much growth lies in going &lt;em&gt;deeper&lt;/em&gt;, not wider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are your thoughts on repetition and immersion? Have you tried applying these principles to your learning or personal growth? Share your experiences below!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Personal Growth</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/05_passions/persona-growth.html</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:31:32 +0100</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/05_passions/persona-growth.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/05_passions/persona-growth/grow.jpeg" alt="Featured image of post Personal Growth" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/05_passions/persona-growth/personalgrowth.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1080&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/05_passions/persona-growth/personalgrowth_hu15341732370339065581.jpg 480w, http://localhost:1313/05_passions/persona-growth/personalgrowth_hu11143947620885413600.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;as&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;
Embark on a journey of &lt;strong&gt;personal growth&lt;/strong&gt; and self-discovery! This blog is all about transforming life, one article, one book, and one action at a time. Starting with a simple curiosity, I dove into the world of personal development, reading about habits, resilience, mindfulness, and purpose. Each insight led to real changes in how I see myself, set goals, and make decisions. Here, I’ll share lessons from books and articles that have had the biggest impact on my life, along with actionable tips and reflections on the changes I’ve experienced. Join me in exploring the power of intentional self-improvement and see how small shifts can lead to profound personal transformation&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
