<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Video Making on Simone Mattioli</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/video-making.html</link>
        <description>Recent content in Video Making on Simone Mattioli</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/video-making/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Birdwatching Experience with SWAROVSKI OPTIK at Le Ali del Frassino Residence (Lake Frassino)</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/swarovski-optik-le-ali-del-frassino.html</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/swarovski-optik-le-ali-del-frassino.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/swarovski-optik-le-ali-del-frassino/invito.png" alt="Featured image of post Birdwatching Experience with SWAROVSKI OPTIK at Le Ali del Frassino Residence (Lake Frassino)" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/swarovski-optik-le-ali-del-frassino/swarovski.jpeg&#34;
	width=&#34;337&#34;
	height=&#34;150&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/swarovski-optik-le-ali-del-frassino/swarovski_hu14759465543953173956.jpeg 480w, http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/swarovski-optik-le-ali-del-frassino/swarovski_hu6023009479089032581.jpeg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Logo Swarovski Optik&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;224&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;539px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, thanks to my project &lt;em&gt;Mountain Fauna Lover&lt;/em&gt;, I had the chance to participate in an exclusive event organized by SWAROVSKI OPTIK Italy at the stunning Frassino Oasis in Peschiera del Garda.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mountain Fauna Lover&lt;/em&gt; began almost as a joke, born from my love for mountains and wildlife. I never imagined it would open doors to such exciting collaborations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/swarovski-optik-le-ali-del-frassino/migrazione.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1200&#34;
	height=&#34;800&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/swarovski-optik-le-ali-del-frassino/migrazione_hu3415763475070476929.jpg 480w, http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/swarovski-optik-le-ali-del-frassino/migrazione_hu15628709650227752216.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Bird Migration&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;150&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;360px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through this project, I’ve been able to experience nature up close, often alongside experts and using top-tier equipment, making each adventure more unforgettable than the last.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/swarovski-optik-le-ali-del-frassino/papera.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;3339&#34;
	height=&#34;2506&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/swarovski-optik-le-ali-del-frassino/papera_hu12033954271459282994.jpg 480w, http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/swarovski-optik-le-ali-del-frassino/papera_hu12014715791681049840.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Duck Photo&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;133&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;319px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time, we were immersed in an extraordinary birdwatching experience with expert guidance and SWAROVSKI OPTIK’s impressive tools, including the NL X52 binoculars and the BTX spotting scope. The day began with a presentation by SWAROVSKI OPTIK Italy’s manager, Franco Cernigliaro, and ornithologist Alessandro Sartori, who introduced us to the bird species we’d encounter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/swarovski-optik-le-ali-del-frassino/binocolo.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;900&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/swarovski-optik-le-ali-del-frassino/binocolo_hu8836717783631905540.jpg 480w, http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/swarovski-optik-le-ali-del-frassino/binocolo_hu7288733104192064040.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;New Swarovski Optik NL-Pures Series&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;213&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;512px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During my meeting with Franco Cernigliaro, the Country Manager of Swarovski Optik Italy, we exchanged inspiring ideas and perspectives on biodiversity and sustainability. It was a remarkable experience to engage with someone equally dedicated to nature and innovation. Our discussion centered on how these themes are fundamental to Swarovski’s mission—not just as marketing strategies but as true core values.
Swarovski Optik actively encourages deeper connections with nature and is committed to supporting sustainable practices and environmentally responsible technologies in their high-precision optics products&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/swarovski-optik-le-ali-del-frassino/pool.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;1080&#34;
	srcset=&#34;http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/swarovski-optik-le-ali-del-frassino/pool_hu480610701872245088.jpg 480w, http://localhost:1313/04_experiences/swarovski-optik-le-ali-del-frassino/pool_hu5052254301236937194.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Ali del Frassino Hotel&amp;rsquo;s Pool&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The observation was incredible—Red-crested Pochards, Tufted Ducks, Teals, and, with a bit of luck, a Marsh Harrier—all appeared in their full beauty, enhanced by the sharpness and clarity of SWAROVSKI’s optics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project has allowed me to build connections with companies like SWAROVSKI OPTIK and explore the world of wildlife in inspiring ways. Who knows what the future holds for &lt;em&gt;Mountain Fauna Lover&lt;/em&gt;… perhaps it will grow from a simple passion into something even greater. Stay tuned for more adventures!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Mountain Fauna Lover</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/03_projects/mountainfaunalover.html</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/03_projects/mountainfaunalover.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/03_projects/mountainfaunalover/logo.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Mountain Fauna Lover" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to MountainFaunaLover! Here, I share my passion for nature, wildlife, and the captivating landscapes of mountain regions. On Instagram, you’ll find a curated collection of my favorite moments in the wilderness, from up-close shots of unique wildlife to breathtaking mountain vistas. Each post is a window into my adventures, capturing the serenity, beauty, and diversity of the natural world that inspires me daily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On YouTube, I dive even deeper. My channel is a space for storytelling, featuring video journeys, wildlife encounters, and conservation insights, bringing viewers along on my explorations. Whether you’re a fellow nature enthusiast or just stopping by for some visual serenity, my content on MountainFaunaLover is dedicated to sharing the awe and importance of our wild places. Join me in celebrating the mountains, fauna, and the fascinating stories they hold!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;youtube-spoiler&#34;&gt;YouTube Spoiler
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;video-wrapper&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
            src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ONGaGgr795k&#34; 
            allowfullscreen 
            title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;
    &gt;
    &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Simo&#39;s Online &amp; Digital Diary</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/03_projects/simos-diary.html</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/03_projects/simos-diary.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/03_projects/simos-diary/logo.jpeg" alt="Featured image of post Simo&#39;s Online &amp; Digital Diary" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to simo&amp;rsquo;s Diary, a place where I love to share&amp;hellip;.da completare&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;scopri-il-mio-canale-youtube-simos-diary&#34;&gt;Scopri il Mio Canale YouTube: Simo&amp;rsquo;s Diary
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Oggi voglio parlarvi del mio canale YouTube, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/@SimosDiary2003&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Simo&amp;rsquo;s Diary&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, dove condivido momenti della mia vita, progetti personali e passioni. Questo spazio nasce dal desiderio di documentare le mie esperienze in modo autentico e trasparente, mostrandovi viaggi, avventure e molto altro ancora.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;perché-ho-creato-simos-diary&#34;&gt;Perché Ho Creato Simo&amp;rsquo;s Diary?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Viviamo in un&amp;rsquo;epoca in cui la tecnologia ci permette di catturare momenti in alta qualità semplicemente con uno smartphone. Non voglio sprecare questa opportunità! Anzi, penso sia fantastico poter registrare e condividere pezzi della mia vita che, altrimenti, resterebbero solo nella memoria. Con Simo&amp;rsquo;s Diary, non solo posso raccogliere questi ricordi per il futuro, ma anche condividerli con chiunque voglia seguirli e magari trovare ispirazione.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cosa-troverai-su-simos-diary&#34;&gt;Cosa Troverai su Simo&amp;rsquo;s Diary
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nel mio canale troverai contenuti che raccontano la &lt;strong&gt;vita vera&lt;/strong&gt; di un ragazzo ambizioso, uno che è pronto a fare sacrifici per raggiungere i propri obiettivi. Voglio mostrarti il mondo senza filtri, lontano dalla perfezione che spesso vediamo online. Attraverso i miei video, ti porterò con me in viaggi, sfide e momenti quotidiani, con l&amp;rsquo;obiettivo di ricordare a me stesso e agli altri quanto sia importante apprezzare ogni cosa che la vita ci offre.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;temi-principali&#34;&gt;Temi Principali:
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gratitudine e Consapevolezza:&lt;/strong&gt; Ogni esperienza che condivido è un’opportunità per riflettere su ciò che abbiamo e per cui possiamo essere grati.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ambizione e Determinazione:&lt;/strong&gt; Simo&amp;rsquo;s Diary è anche la storia di un ragazzo che vuole tanto dalla vita e non ha paura di lottare per realizzare i suoi sogni.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Autenticità:&lt;/strong&gt; Non mi interessa mostrare una vita perfetta, ma piuttosto offrire un&amp;rsquo;immagine reale della mia esistenza, con le sue sfide, difficoltà e non solo i suoi traguardi.-&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Crescita personale&lt;/strong&gt; Il mio percorso e pensieri / skills che ho sviluppato durante questo processo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pensieri&lt;/strong&gt; Quando mi viene in mente un pensiero, oppure inizio un ragionamento quando possibile inizio a registrare in modo tale da poter poi riascoltarmi anche in futuro e capire come la pensavo in un determinato momento della mia vita&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;un-invito-a-seguire-le-proprie-passioni&#34;&gt;Un Invito a Seguire le Proprie Passioni
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Con Simo&amp;rsquo;s Diary, voglio ispirarti a vivere pienamente e a usare le risorse che abbiamo oggi per creare qualcosa di significativo. La mia speranza è che i miei video possano spingerti a inseguire i tuoi obiettivi e a coltivare la gratitudine per le piccole cose della vita senza però dimenticarti la cosa che pià mi sta a cuore ultimamente, il fatto di &lt;strong&gt;godersi la vita&lt;/strong&gt;, quindi vivere ogni momento e sfida con il sorriso e gioia perchè il nostro periodo di permanenza su questa terra è molto limitato e non vale la pena scoraggiarsi e viversela male.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Se ti piace l&amp;rsquo;idea di scoprire avventure, riflessioni autentiche e la vita vera di un ragazzo che insegue i suoi sogni, visita il mio canale e iscriviti!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grazie per aver letto, e spero di vederti presto tra i miei follower su YouTube!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;rimani-in-contatto-con-me&#34;&gt;Rimani in contatto con me
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Seguimi su YouTube e sui social per rimanere aggiornato sulle mie avventure e scoprire di più sulla mia vita e i miei progetti!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
