<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Productivity on Simone Mattioli</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/productivity.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Productivity on Simone Mattioli</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:31:32 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/productivity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The 20th century Trap</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/02_thought/trap.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 19:31:32 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/02_thought/trap.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;detached-from-stimuli&#34;&gt;Detached from stimuli&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We live in an age of constant stimulation, a constant flow of notifications, updates and digital content that keep us constantly &amp;ldquo;connected&amp;rdquo; but, at the same time, drastically reduce our ability to concentrate. Every day, we are bombarded with visual and auditory stimuli through social media, messaging apps, entertainment platforms, which now guide our lives both online and offline.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-loss-of-attention-span&#34;&gt;The Loss of Attention Span&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This situation scares me. I have noticed, especially during the pandemic, how much social media has taken on the role of &amp;ldquo;directors&amp;rdquo; of our lives. People talk about news, trends, and aspects of other people&amp;rsquo;s lives that they have learned on social media, as if these have replaced real experiences. Our attention span has reduced to almost absurd levels: we are incapable of standing in line or waiting without taking out our phones in search of new stimuli. This constant search for instant gratification through digital devices deprives us of the ability to fully live in the moment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simo Performance Coach Consultant</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/03_projects/performance.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/03_projects/performance.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;stay-tunedmore-info-are-comming-soon-meanwhile-you-can-contact-me-via-email-for-info&#34;&gt;STAY TUNED&amp;hellip;more info are comming soon, meanwhile you can contact me via email for INFO&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
