<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Simone Mattioli</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/03_projects.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Simone Mattioli</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/03_projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>EPICURE Hackathon GPU - October 2024</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/03_projects/epicure-hackathon-2024.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/03_projects/epicure-hackathon-2024.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;EPICURE Hackathon&lt;/strong&gt;, held from October 28-31, 2024, brought together developers, researchers, and enthusiasts from across Europe to dive deep into the world of &lt;strong&gt;GPU programming and high-performance computing (HPC)&lt;/strong&gt;. This event was hosted in collaboration with &lt;strong&gt;CINECA&lt;/strong&gt;, one of the leading HPC centers in Europe, renowned for its contributions to scientific computing and advanced research.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The hackathon was meticulously structured, featuring both hands-on labs and theoretical sessions, designed to empower participants with the latest skills in &lt;strong&gt;CUDA programming&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;OpenACC&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;GPU optimization techniques&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mountain Fauna Lover</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/03_projects/mountain-fauna-lover.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/03_projects/mountain-fauna-lover.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to MountainFaunaLover! Here, I share my passion for nature, wildlife, and the captivating landscapes of mountain regions. On Instagram, you’ll find a curated collection of my favorite moments in the wilderness, from up-close shots of unique wildlife to breathtaking mountain vistas. Each post is a window into my adventures, capturing the serenity, beauty, and diversity of the natural world that inspires me daily.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On YouTube, I dive even deeper. My channel is a space for storytelling, featuring video journeys, wildlife encounters, and conservation insights, bringing viewers along on my explorations. Whether you’re a fellow nature enthusiast or just stopping by for some visual serenity, my content on MountainFaunaLover is dedicated to sharing the awe and importance of our wild places. Join me in celebrating the mountains, fauna, and the fascinating stories they hold!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simo Performance Coach Consultant</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/03_projects/performance.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/03_projects/performance.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;stay-tunedmore-info-are-comming-soon-meanwhile-you-can-contact-me-via-email-for-info&#34;&gt;STAY TUNED&amp;hellip;more info are comming soon, meanwhile you can contact me via email for INFO&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simo&#39;s Online &amp; Digital Diary</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/03_projects/home.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/03_projects/home.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to simo&amp;rsquo;s Diary, a place where I love to share&amp;hellip;.da completare&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;discover-my-youtube-channel-simos-diary&#34;&gt;Discover My YouTube Channel: Simo&amp;rsquo;s Diary&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today I want to tell you about my YouTube channel, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/@SimosDiary2003&#34;&gt;Simo&amp;rsquo;s Diary&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, where I share moments of my life, personal projects and passions. This space was born from the desire to document my experiences in an authentic and transparent way, showing you trips, adventures and much more.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-did-i-create-simos-diary&#34;&gt;Why Did I Create Simo&amp;rsquo;s Diary?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We live in an era where technology allows us to capture moments in high quality simply with a smartphone. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to waste this opportunity! In fact, I think it&amp;rsquo;s fantastic to be able to record and share pieces of my life that, otherwise, would only remain in memory. With Simo&amp;rsquo;s Diary, not only can I collect these memories for the future, but also share them with anyone who wants to follow them and maybe find inspiration.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
